Hello everyone, welcome and thanks for
joining us. My name is Robert. I'll be
your host. This is our history program
on the John F. Kennedy assassination.
Thanks so much for joining us. Let's go
ahead and get started. So the Kennedy
assassination took place on November
22nd, 1963.
So 62 years ago today, uh the
assassination took place and thought we
would do once again our annual program
on this. I think we started doing these
back in um 2020 during COVID. So amazing
it's been that long. And we'll talk
about different aspects of the Kennedy
assassination both before, during, and
after this monumental event. Uh in
particular, what I thought I would do is
it's not just going to be about the
shooting. Um, and then you know we go
home. Uh, thought we'd give maybe a
little different perspective on things.
We'll talk about the historical context
of things that took place before,
during, and after the assassination.
There's a lot of, um, fictitious stuff
floating around about the Kennedy
assassination. So, we talked about fact
versus fiction. Um, I'm joining you from
Texas. And so I thought we would include
the Texas connections to the um
assassination, not just Dallas, but also
um San Antonio, Houston, Austin, Fort
Worth, etc. Uh, and then I didn't want
to just be like a total downer and talk
about the assassination itself without
including some information on President
Kennedy's legacy.
So,
my name is Robert. I'll be your host. A
little bit about myself. I'm originally
from Detroit, Michigan. I was an art
history major in college at the
University of Michigan. Um, let's see.
I've lived in Southern California,
Washington DC, and now Texas in addition
to Detroit. And for many years, I've
done these in-person tours related to
presidents and first ladies. Just so you
know, I'm an independent. I'm neither a
Democrat or Republican. And I was
talking about this with my wife,
Michelle. I've actually done a lot of
tours in person related to the
presidents and first ladies. So when I
lived in Southern California, I did
tours of the Nixon Museum and the Reagan
Museum in Washington DC. I did a tours
of the Smithsonian History Museum, the
Smithsonian Art Museum, the White House
Gardens, the Lincoln Assassination, the
Booth Escape Route, the Lincoln
Memorial, Elellanena Roosevelt, Harry
Truman, uh John F. Kennedy and
Jacqueline Kennedy in Washington DC, and
the Watergate All the President's
Mentor. And here in Texas, I've given
tours of the Kennedy assassination in
Dallas, also the Lynden Johnson Museum
in Austin, and the George W. Bush Museum
in Dallas. So interesting. I didn't
realize I had done this many of these
until I was talking about it uh with my
wife Michelle earlier. So FYI in that.
And we also have our good friend Patty
joining us. Hi Patty, how are you? Oh,
and as far as most inspiring person, I'm
going to go with Ulysiz Srant. How about
that? And hi Patty, how are you? Do you
want to introduce yourself?
And who's your most inspiring person?
>> Uh yeah,
[laughter]
Patty from um Portsouth, New Hampshire.
The famous Portsouth, New Hampshire. And
um let's see. I'm I'm going to cheat and
do two two. I'm combining two from the
last couple of nights. Abraham Lincoln
just for
the the incredible job he did at a very
critical time. And um also Ken Burns who
has taught us to love and appreciate
American history in a much deeper way
than we might otherwise have.
>> Okay. Well, awesome. Well, thanks Patty.
Thanks for joining us. We also have our
good friend Brad joining us. Hi Brad.
How are you? Do you want to introduce
yourself? And you have the most
inspiring person.
>> Brad, I'm calling from Falling Waters,
Eastern Panhandle of West Virginia.
uh originally from Connecticut. And I
guess the most
meaningful person in in American history
anyway for me at this point would be
George Washington, but there are others.
>> Okay. All right. Very excellent choices.
Um I did see that our friend Joanne is
joining us from Dallas. Hi Joanne. I
don't know if you can hear me, but um if
you want to chime in at any point in
time, feel free to do so. Joanne um
lives with me here in the Dallas Fort
Worth area and she's super knowledgeable
about history and she gave a really cool
tour on the women's suffrage movement um
a few months back and we're also going
to be doing a classical music program
with Joan at some time in the future.
Hey there Joanne, how you doing?
Welcome.
>> Hi. Yeah, I'm doing fine.
>> Anything um you want to introduce
yourself and do you have a most
inspiring historical person?
>> Oh yes, Alice Paul and the Silent
Sentinels. Um, yeah, I think without
Alice Paul, the 19th the n it would have
taken 10 times more effort to get that
19th amendment to the into the
constitution
and u say this point blank she deserves
as much recognition as Martin Luther
King Gandhi and Mandela.
>> Okay, awesome. Well, thanks so much for
joining us. I hope you don't mind me
putting you on the spot. I saw you have
>> surprised [laughter]
feel free to chime in. I did I did push
for getting uh some uh programs on, you
know, the great classics.
>> Um
>> and I'm just I'm I'm looking forward to
seeing uh again Amadeus and um Immortal
Beloved. I saw them years and years ago.
I'm looking forward to seeing him again.
>> Well, thank you. I appreciate that. Be
reaching out to you very very soon as
soon as um Okay.
>> work calm down. Um let's see. All right.
Let's go ahead and get started. So, John
F. Kennedy. You may know this already,
but he was the fourth American president
that was assassinated. The first was, of
course, Abraham Lincoln in 1865. Um, the
number two and number three uh
presidents aren't as well known. So,
President James Garfield was
assassinated in 1881,
so just 16 years after Abraham Lincoln.
And then 20 years later in 1901,
President William McKinley was
assassinated. And I feel like Garfield
and McKinley um not completely forgotten
about but not as well known as Lincoln
and Kennedy. Well, maybe
>> I think they're both well known for the
vice presidents who took who had to fill
their shoes.
>> Yeah. Do you want to talk about that
briefly? I don't want to go off too much
on a tangent. No, just Chester Arthur um
who was a Tamony Hall
stalwart um ended up being the one who
really ended the patronage system in DC
and established the civil service and
McKinley of course um made way for Teddy
Roosevelt who uh accomplished a lot of
major things. So, um, like I said, both
probably better known for their,
although Chester Arthur probably isn't
that well known to many people who
aren't familiar with, um, the whole
patronage issue and and what happens
with corrupt appointments versus the
civil service system that tried to
eliminate as much of that corruption.
But it was the somebody who was who had
a beef about not getting a patronage
appointment that actually killed
Garfield. So
>> it was kind of a triumvirate of people
that brought about um the end of that.
So
>> and then you have Andrew Johnson taking
over after Abraham Lincoln and Lynden
Johnson taking over after Kennedy. So
kind of a interesting mix of successors
um to the presidents. Uh let's talk
briefly about the historical context of
the Kennedy assassination. We'll get
into again the actual shooting itself um
a little bit later, but some historical
context first. So, interestingly enough,
uh, John F. Kennedy was killed on
November 22nd, 1963. He had actually
just celebrated his 10-year wedding
anniversary to Jackie. They were married
on September 12th, 1953.
Nice wedding photo of them. If you want
to learn more about the Bouvier Kennedy
wedding, um, we did a program on this, I
think maybe a couple years ago. Oh,
yeah. We did it for the um anniversary
uh back in 2023 and it's on both our
Washington DC History and Culture
YouTube channel and our Texas History
and Culture channel. Um it basically
like a walkthrough of what it would have
been like to attend their wedding. So
you can go check that out. And let's
see, 1963 was a big year for a lot of
other things, not just the Kennedy
assassination in August 28th, so just a
few weeks before um President Kennedy
went to Texas. Dr. Dr. Martin Luther
King Jr. delivered his I have a dream
speech on the National Mall.
And President Kennedy was one of four
great American leaders that were shot
and killed during a very short 4 and a
half year span. So of course you have
President Kennedy, also Malcolm X, uh
Dr. King, and then President Kennedy's
brother Robert. So a very tumultuous
time. uh a lot of political and social
upheaval taking place in America at this
point in time.
Um let's see. I like to think of the
Kennedys in my opinion as kind of the
first quote unquote modern first couple.
Um, and what I mean by that is if you
think about their predecessors, the
Eisenhowers and the Truman's um, in
particular, um, yeah, they were covered
in the media and, you know, a lot of
people were following what they were
doing, but when the Kennedys came into
the White House, they took it to a whole
another level and it's kind of been like
that ever since. I mean, pretty much
anything the president and the first
lady does is cloely scrutinized by the
press for better or for worse. Um, and
in my opinion, that really took off
during the Kennedy administration. Uh,
they were frequently the subject of
magazine covers, whether it was Time or
Life or Look. Um, and I've gone back and
looked at like magazine covers that the
Eisenhowers and the Truman's on, and
yeah, they were covered, but nothing
like the Kennedys, and this kind of uh
has continued on to present day. Oh,
someone uh Elizabeth mentioned that
Megar Evers was also um assassinated
1963. Thanks. I appreciate you
mentioning that. Um, and you know, not
just like political or mainstream
magazines, but all different types of
stuff. So, you have Sports Illustrated,
Ebony, and not even just American
magazines. There's Canadian magazines
and French and British magazines. Here's
Paris Match. Um, and they're on the
cover of that. So, just an incredible
amount of media coverage and public
fascination with the Kennedys. And then
also, this is the beginning of the
television era. And so that also plays a
part in the Kennedys uh being like quote
unquote the first modern uh first
couple. Um and I thought this was an
interesting statistic. So this is
American television ownership by
household. So you can see that in 1950
only 9% of the households in the US had
a television set and in 1948 pretty much
nobody had one. Fast forward a decade or
10 years to 1960, uh, the year that
President Kennedy was elected, that
shoots up to 87%.
Um, and so he's going into the White
House at a time when this television
thing is really surging. Um, and that
really plays a part and kind of
documenting what's going on with
President Kennedy and Mrs. Kennedy. And
you know, if you think about President
Kennedy, there's all these television
moments that he was involved in.
everything from the Kennedy Nixon
debates to his inauguration to the
assassination, the funeral, etc. And if
you think back to Truman and Eisenhower,
they were both very successful
presidents in their own right. Can you
how many like video clips can you think
of Truman or Eisenhower? I mean, yeah,
there's a few here and there like uh
Truman firing MacArthur and uh
Eisenhower gave a important speech on
the Cold War, but again, President
Kennedy really kind of took things to a
whole another level. Not that he did it
by himself. I mean, he's coming into
office when television is surging. Um,
and so that really plays a part in kind
of recording u what took place in his
administration. And if you think about
again all these television moments that
Kennedy's the Kennedys were associated
with. So the Kennedy Nixon debates were
televised. Uh you've probably seen John
F. Kennedy's inauguration speech, ask
not what your country can do for you,
ask what you can do for your country.
Jackie's famous White House tour, the
assassination with the Zapruder film.
Uh, even the Kennedy funeral with John
Jr. giving the salute. Just all this
television stuff uh is really
interesting how it recorded them much
more closely than his predecessors were
covered. Um, let's see. Why don't we
check in quickly with Patty, Brad, and
Joanne? Any thoughts on the Kennedys in
this media era, so to speak?
Well, obviously the fact that they were
the first first family in I don't know
how long uh because I don't really
follow the children that much, but they
were the first in many many years to
have young young children. And also, um
Jackie had given birth, I think, um just
shortly before um the inauguration. And
then um yeah, because John's birthday
was in November, I think. That was
>> and um she actually had a miscarriage
while they were in the White House
>> or a premature birth I think
>> Patrick.
>> Yeah, we'll talk about that in just a
little bit later.
>> So that would have attracted again
you're talking about the baby boom
generation. So most of the families at
that time um had children.
[clears throat]
[laughter] So that was a a an an aspect
that tied a lot of people together.
Before we go on, I just Yes. Okay.
you've noticed it because I was going to
ask people
and we took we took care of it also.
>> Uh Jackie wanted uh the White House to
be the American Versailles and I I think
she succeeded very brilliantly
[laughter]
and uh yeah the Kennedys they brought
glamour to the White House. They were
masters of the media. Um, a lot of
Berliners who heard his famous speech
know is I'm Berlin, pardon my awful
German, said uh, they said it was such a
revelation because they said previously,
you know, they had been governed by
their grandfathers and to see some of
their own generations, someone who was,
you know, hip and cool and all that, uh,
being in leadership, it was very
inspiring to them.
>> You know, that's a great point. I forgot
to mention Yeah. his speech in Germany.
A number of people have seen that as
well.
>> Yeah. No, it's amazing. I saw I I
watched the video. It's amazing how well
it holds up. I mean, [snorts]
>> um let's see. Brad, Patty, any other
thoughts before we move on?
>> Uh no,
just again to ask people to try to
moderate their comments a little bit to
you know.
Okay. All right. Let's continue on. Um,
so again, the Kennedy Nixon presidential
debate, um, a really defining moment in
television history. There hadn't been a
presidential debate, um, like this
before. And while there's been many
presidential debates since then, I would
argue this is the most famous uh,
presidential debate. So, a
>> just a comment on that that um people
who listened to that on the radio
thought one candidate won that debate
and people who saw it on TV thought a
completely different candidate won that
debate.
>> Correct.
Let's see.
>> Yeah, I saw there was a really cute
comment. You know, Jean Tyranny, the
movie star, dated JFK.
Um, and when he won the presidency, uh,
she sent him a congratulatory note even
though she voted for Nixon.
>> I thought that was very gracious.
>> Interesting. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. That sort of bracationist that
doesn't happen nowadays.
>> No. Um, and then again, another
television moment, the Kennedy
inauguration. I mean, think back. How
many quotes from a presidential
inauguration can you reel off? um maybe
like some recent ones, but uh you know
the ask not what your country can do for
you, ask what you can do for your
country. I mean perhaps uh one of the
most famous uh presidential inaugural
lines in history and of course that was
a television moment. And then what about
Jackie's White House tour? Um I mean
honestly nothing against all the other
first ladies. Can you think of any other
first lady that had like major
television moment like that that was
really like a history defining uh type
of thing
>> that was kind of whole another level?
What's that?
>> Even in black and white, she came across
beautiful. I mean,
and and very sophisticated and able to
present the White House in a way that
made people feel like she really
believed that it was their home, not
just hers.
Yeah, maybe that was the cognitive
dissonance that I keep experiencing when
we see that Jackie movie because she
always emanated grace no matter what she
was doing. And that is not the part that
comes through I think in that movie that
we saw last night.
>> That's sort of a built-in thing and I
don't think Natalie Portman had it. I'm
sorry to say.
>> Yeah. No, I would um I can see where
you're coming from in that pride. Um,
and then of course the assassination
itself. I mean the Sruder film. I mean
I'm sure 99% of the people here have
seen it or at least familiar um with it.
Another television moment. And then um
you know it's just been played over and
over again. Uh, and it's probably if you
if you think of terms of video footage
of the president, I can't think of
anything else that if you had to make a
list of like the most watched things,
um, as tragic as this is, I can't think
of any other presidents who's like a a
video clip of them, um, is as like
well-known or widely seen, um, as this
one, especially from like a historical
context. Maybe something um, more
recent. Then of course there's Walter
Kankite um announcing the death or
announcing first that President Kennedy
had been shot and then later announcing
that he had died. Um another important
television moment. I mean I've I saw a
article um a few months back. It was
like the 10 most defining moments in
television history and this was one of
them just because of the significance of
it. Um and then of course Oswald he was
shot and killed uh in Dallas on live TV.
So another television moment. Um, and
then the funeral was also broadcast. Um,
so if you talk to someone that was alive
back then, it was pretty much non-stop
programming, which was really unusual.
We're kind of used to that now in the
24-hour news cycle. Um, but that was
pretty unusual for that era. So again,
all these um television moments in
addition to the magazine coverage and
newspaper coverage and different media
really makes the Kennedys kind of the
first modern first couple, so to speak.
I think that's the first and only time I
can remember the TV being on most of the
time that we were awake. Um, and on a
working farm, that's very unusual that
somebody was always paying attention
[laughter] to.
>> Okay. Well, that's a good um that's
interesting memory, Patty. Thanks.
Appreciate that.
>> Those three things, you know what I
mean? It's like it it was it was sort of
it was so disorienting that people felt
like they needed to be attached. And I
really suspect that was when uh Walter
Kankite became the most trusted man in
America for quite a few years
thereafter.
>> Yeah. It wasn't just for announcing the
death of Jim Morrison. I mean, it was
[laughter]
I thought I thought that was funny
because when I was researching the door,
I actually didn't know that he had made
the announcement about his death. So, I
thought that was interesting. But
anyway,
>> all I could think of was the JFK
announcement. So, I was kind of
surprised myself when you showed that.
But uh yeah, it was actually I mean a
lot of people think that when he finally
gave his impressions after visiting
Vietnam, I think a lot of people
including LBJ thought that um that was
the turning point right there.
>> Oh yeah. Um all right. So what were the
Kenny's actually? Why were they in
Dallas? Why weren't they in Washington
DC during this time? So let's go through
some of that. Um this is really
interesting. I find this fascinating.
C-SPAN um for several different times
over course of recent history. Um they
surveyed professional historians and
said, "Hey, who do you think is the best
and worst president?" And rank them all
from high to low. You can see Abraham
Lincoln, he's been consistently the top
president according to, again, this is
not just random people on the street.
This is professional historians, uh
hundreds of them. Um and Abraham Lincoln
is always at the top of the list. Um, so
you can see that George Washington
second. And so look, look down and okay,
wow, John F. Kennedy, he's ranked number
eight. That's pretty amazing when you
consider the number of presidents we
have. So that's very um impressive. And
also it's been very consistent.
>> We don't have a We don't have a picture
that you're referring to.
>> Why is that? Uh, let's see.
>> All I have is Okay, there it goes. Yep.
>> Oh, thank you. Appreciate that. Sorry, I
must have pressed the wrong button. Um,
anyway, this is the C-SPAN Presidential
Historian Survey. Um they surveyed
hundreds of historians and you can see
Abraham Lincoln he's always been at the
top of the list. Um but John F. Kennedy
a very respectable number eight although
once he was six. Um so when you consider
the number of people we've had in the
Oval Office that's a very distinguished
uh record so to speak. Um however John
F. Kennedy wasn't always um that
popular. So he just barely won the 1960
presidential election. In my opinion,
uh, this is one of the most studied and
talked about elections in American
history, uh, just because of the
interesting dynamics and how close it
was. And John F. Kennedy won the states
of Illinois and Texas by a combined
55,000 votes. Had he not won both of
those states, Nixon would have been
elected president. And so you think,
well, 55,000 divided by two, if 27,500
people in Texas and Illinois would have
voted for Nixon, he would have won the
1960 presidential election. Just to show
you how close that was. And then um John
F. Kennedy when he goes into the White
House, he's very popular. Uh this is his
presidential approval rating. Um, you
can see and you know it's funny because
in recent times no president has gotten
anywhere near this kind of approval
rating. We're so divided as a nation now
um on all sides that people really can't
look past their political preferences. I
mean uh it's been a long time since
anyone was in the 70s for president but
President Kennedy was. Um but you can
see his low point was right around the
time he was assassinated. So there was a
lot of frustration with him and his
administration. And so yeah, he's
popular now. He was popular when he
first went into the White House, but
when he goes down to Dallas, he's at a
low point in his popularity. And he's
starting to crank up the 1964
re-election campaign. And remember,
Texas is a really key state. If he lost
that, he would have lost the election.
So he's like, you know what? I'm going
to go down there and try and shore up
support, so to speak. And so his team
decides that it would be good for him to
make a trip down there in the year
before the election of 1964.
Um, now President Kennedy travels with
his wife Jackie and that was a big PR
move for him whenever she accompanied
him. she would draw a huge amount of
press coverage and people would come out
and just kind of a lot of buzz so to
speak wherever she went um either by
herself or with President Kennedy. So,
it's really kind of interesting just to
look at these photos of them and the the
cameras and the videos and the people
coming out to take a look at them. It
was really kind of like movie staresque
um so to speak.
Now, we mentioned this briefly before.
Um, a lot of people don't realize that
when President Kennedy was killed,
Jackie was still mourning the death of
her son. So, she gave birth to baby
Patrick and he only ended up living for
39 hours and he ended up dying on August
9th, 1963. And again, President
Kennedy's killed on November 22nd. So
this um event quite a few people know
about it but it's kind of been like
forgotten about because it's really been
overshadowed by the death of President
Kenny. So I imagine this in a 15week
span she lost her son Patrick um who had
been alive for 39 hours but then she
also lost her husband. Um, so the fact
that she was able to kind of continue on
and endure uh after the death of her
husband,
really, really incredible.
And so, the Texas trip is really kind of
the unofficial kickoff to the 1964
re-election campaign. Oh, and then I'm
sorry, I forgot to mention, um, Jackie
really had a lot of health issues after
this. She was hospitalized for several
days and in the 15 weeks after her son
died, she was kind of a recluse. She
pretty much just stayed inside the White
House. And I'm not faulting her or
blaming her in any way. Um but she was
having a lot of physical health um
problems after that. And so she really
hadn't been out all that much in public.
But when President Kennedy's going down
to Texas, she's going to come along. And
so it's kind of like her re uh emergence
on the public stage. And that's really
adds an interesting dynamic. I mean,
think how differently uh this event
would have been portrayed or remembered
um if President Kenny say, had been
traveling by himself. It would have been
a very different um type of event, so to
speak. Um let's see. And then I always
thought this was an interesting set of
photos. So, obviously, President and
Mrs. Kennedy, they're living in the
White House. What did they do on their
last night together in the White House?
Well, they had a little like mini get
together uh where the indoor white house
Christmas tree was unveiled. Not the
famous outdoor tree that people go and
see the public um but an indoor tree.
And they had a small kind of reception
um for friends and family members. And
so they ended up posing um in front of
the tree. So this is Wednesday, November
20th, and about
39 hours later um he would be shot and
killed. So, kind of an interesting set
of photos of them standing in front of
the tree. Um, and then after the
reception was over and they posed for
this photo, they went up to the private
quarters of the White House and they
started the tenuous process of signing
all their Christmas cards. So, you know,
remember back in the day when people
used to [laughter] actually send
Christmas cards in the mail? Well, if
you're the president, the first lady,
you have to send thousands of them and
they're going to sign all these. So, uh,
Wednesday, November 20th was them
starting the process of signing all
these cards. And I think if I'm not
mistaken, they signed about a hundred of
them um before they retired for the
evening. And then uh the next morning,
they begin their trip to Texas. And it
was a three-day trip. They're going to
fly from Washington DC to San Antonio uh
on Thursday morning. Thursday there it's
going to be a whirlwind trip to San
Antonio, Houston, and Fort Worth. Friday
they're going to [clears throat] um
spend the night in Fort Worth, then go
to Dallas and then on to Austin and then
the Lynden Johnson Ranch. Uh they're
going to spend the day Saturday there
and then fly home Saturday evening. So a
whirlwind trip and um I think maybe some
people even in Texas might not realize
that the Kennedys were in San Antonio,
Houston, and Fort Worth before they went
to Dallas. It wasn't like they just flew
from uh DC to Dallas. Interesting in
that regard. Um so again, a real
whirlwind trip. He's going to fly along
with his wife to San Antonio. Then
they're going to fly to Houston. Oops.
Uh then they're going to flap to Fort
Worth, then to Dallas, and if he hadn't
been assassinated, he was going to
continue on to Austin, and then he was
going to go to a barbecue uh at the
Lynden Johnson Ranch and spend the night
there before flying home to Washington
DC. So, that was the plan.
And let's see, we'll talk about them
departing um Washington DC in just a
moment, but before we do that, Joanne,
Patty, Brad, any thoughts on the
upcoming trip?
Well, yeah, I got uh there was a lovely
coffee table book from the Dallas Museum
of Art. It's called Hotel Texas, an art
exhibit, art exhibition for the
president and Mrs. John F. Kennedy.
That's the way they talked in 1963.
And yeah, they stayed in the Hotel Texas
in Fort Worth and they surprised the
Kennedys by having a lot of beautiful
art from all the art museums in Texas
and uh they did an exhibit. They got all
those paintings, you know, from the
Kimble and all the museums in the area
and they didn't they did an ex
exhibition of that um you know, like
during one of the big anniversaries of
Kennedy's death here. So, um, no, I'm
very fortunate to have this coffee table
book.
>> Oh, thanks. I appreciate you mentioning
that because, yeah, that's like a really
big deal in the Dallas Fort Worth area
that the people rallied together to
solicit these well-known paintings by
like Monae and Van Go and stuff, private
collection on display in their hotel
suite.
>> Yeah. And they did they didn't do it
just because they know uh Jackie, you
know, love the arts. They wanted to show
the world that uh you know Dallas and
Fort Worth are not just cow towns. You
[snorts] know at that time in the 60s um
yeah a lot of Texans they were very
eager to show the world that you know
we're sophisticated even though we have
the accents and you know we can talk um
art and science just as well as anybody
else.
>> Culture and all that kind of stuff. So
yeah, that's a great point. Thanks
Joanne. Appreciate that. What about
Patty? Brad, any other thoughts?
No, but thank you for contributing that
that Yeah, I I get what you what you're
talking about.
>> And I just want to say also about that
Jackie film, which I like a lot. I
[snorts] think what they were trying to
do was get under the lid of, you know,
Jackie's very Jackie's elegance and
poise and, you know, show all the
torment she was going through because
she really went through a lot. Um, of
course with the death of their son and
then the assassination. I mean, um, it
was really quite traumatic and she had
suicidal thoughts and that's what I
thought. I thought Natalie Portman was
trying to, you know, get beyond the lid,
especially with her, you know, constant
smoking. [laughter]
>> Yeah. Was the director talked about he
wanted to be a psychological profile,
not necessarily a historical profile.
>> But made me think about the the
premature birth and the death of the
baby. Yes.
We hadn't known about that when that was
happening. Now they understand how
horrific smoking is for pregnancies.
>> Oh yeah. And then I've also read um
doctors have said if their child was
born now, he would have survived back at
this point in time.
>> Um they didn't have the technology and
the knowledge to save him. So that's an
unfortunate um event as well. What about
you, Brad? Any thoughts before we
continue on?
>> Well, I think um I'm ready to continue
on. I think it was a wonderful trip. It
was a very con conclusive political
trip. Some of the other books and things
have suggested that there was a lot of
infighting between Johnson and Governor
Connelly and some of the others, but and
I guess this show of unity was going to
try to draw them all together.
>> Oh, yeah. That is kind of one of the
myths. I'm not saying that that didn't
exist, but um yeah, hold your hold your
people should hold their opinion on
that.
for uh a moment till we um go a little
bit further. So um if you're not
familiar with Washington DC, um how the
president usually travels is they
usually take the helicopter from the
White House to Andrews Air Force Base,
which is in Maryland, and then they fly
off on the jet plane to wherever they
have to go. So that's what the Kennedys
did. They took off from Andrews Air
Force Base early Thursday morning. Uh
and here they are. I thought I'd include
a lot of photos.
For whatever reason, I've always enjoyed
looking at these um historical pictures
just to kind of get a different
perspective on things. So, here's
Jacqueline and John F. Kennedy. They're
getting off the helicopter, Marine One,
which is over here, and they're heading
towards Air Force One, to head off to
Dallas. And they're really going to have
a long day. They left Dallas early in
the morning, and they got into Fort
Worth, I think I'm not mistaken, around
midnight. Um, and they were doing all
these public events. So, really, uh,
long day. Notice, uh, John F. Kenny's
got a hat in his hand. Uh, which is
interesting because he didn't wear a lot
of hats.
>> And yeah, when they got into Fort Worth
and went to their suite, the Hotel
Texas, they were just delighted to see
all these beautiful paintings. And uh
yeah, Jackie and Jack, they really
enjoyed all the artwork.
>> Yeah. And really liked the last uh
artwork they saw. Um
>> Yeah. That's that makes it all the more
poignant.
And then, okay, so they arrive in San
Antonio, Texas, the Alamo City, and
here's the car at the airport. So, they
fly the car in a separate plane. Um, you
can see all the people gathered at the
airport. I've flown in and out of San
Antonio airport many, many times. Um,
and okay, here they are coming off the
plane. Um, Jackie looking very
well-dressed as always. Their husband,
he's still holding his hat. They're
walking hand in hand down the stairs.
And so you see these pictures, not a
lot, but sometimes in different media
contexts. I think it's interesting is
because the Texas trip, Jackie's known
for her pink Chanel suit, which we'll
talk about a little bit later. Um, but
here she's wearing different outfit.
>> President Kennedy is all smiles as well.
And again, he was used to traveling on
his own because Jackie had been even
before uh Patrick's birth, you know, she
was pregnant. And so her travel was
really limited beforehand as well. So
this is really the first time in many
months that they've gone out um on a
public trip like this.
This is a good uh photo though. If you
look at behind Jackie, all of those guys
are older guys and it really other than
the FBI guys who tended to be, you know,
a little younger, but the Secret Service
guys, I should say. Um, but yeah, that
that was always set off because he he
was always among people that looked a
lot older, too.
>> Mhm.
>> Good point, Patty. Appreciate that. And
notice they're all smiles.
>> And look at those gloves that Jackie is
wearing.
>> Yeah, you don't see those anymore.
>> Very class.
>> And even President Kennedy, I mean, he
just looks so comfortable. I mean, I
have to wear a suit once in a while and
I'm always like, "Oh god.
>> [laughter]
>> looks very compound. Maybe because I
haven't worn it as often as he did. I
don't know. Or maybe because I don't
look as good in my suit as he looked at
me. But anyway, um yeah, just really
interesting pictures because it's kind
of a like I said a somber the whole trip
because of the assassination. Very
somber. But when you look at these
photos, you know, from earlier in the
day, it's everyone's all smiles and the
sun is shining and you know, all that
kind of stuff. So really interesting.
>> Yeah. And I just want to make it very
clear that I have no illusions about the
marriage of Jack and Jackie or, you
know, all the things that the Kennedys
did.
>> Now, I I see some comments. You know, I
always thought that Jackie was a
long-suffering wife. She just looks
nervouses of trying to please. Believe
me, this was, you know, the the Mad Men
era and um so yeah, I have no illusions.
>> Oh, yeah. No, I get that. I get where
people could say that, but on the new
hand, I mean, look at the pictures, not
just these, but the ones in the future.
I mean, she's smiling from ear to ear,
and yeah, you can fake that, but I don't
know. I kind of think maybe that's uh
there's some truth to that, but maybe
not as extreme as some people might
think, but that's just my opinion. Um,
hey,
>> what's that?
>> Contemporary accounts. Even Cruchef, who
was not particularly like suave, um, was
totally charmed by Jacqueline Kennedy. I
mean people who were contemporary were
charmed by her and
>> Oh yeah, de Gaul.
>> Yeah, it it's uh it's
notice notably frosty and egotistical.
Um yeah, contemp it almost feels like a
sort of revisionist thing going on like
to try to denigrate. Um, and one thing I
will say is that this assassination
really spawned the whole cottage
industry of conspiracy theory even long
before computers. And I I sometimes
wonder if part of the Yes, it was a very
interesting and complicated
relationship, marriage, whatever you
want to call it. But I cannot
overemphasize how much young families,
which the United States was pretty much
overwhelmed by young families then. And
these were the baby boom generation. Um,
and they were just immensely popular
among
younger families. I don't I don't know
another way to say it. I I can't
remember a lot of people having negative
things to say. And I do remember almost
everybody that I knew having a picture
of JFK in their house.
>> So,
>> yeah. Like when I see this photo, I
don't know. Do you think she's faking
that smile? It doesn't look like it to
me. I mean, I could be mistaken.
>> Here's another thing. Um, you know, my
family was Catholic of Irish Italian
lineage and really to have a Catholic
president, I mean, that that was that
was a that was a big step forward in
that time.
>> A lot of Catholics had Pope John Paul uh
Pope John the 23rd, excuse me, and JFK
almost side by side.
And a somebody mentioned a a famous
quote. No, he said, "I'm the guy who
accompanied U. Jacqueline Kennedy to
Paris,
>> right? And I enjoyed it very much.
>> Exactly.
>> Um well, another thing is you know the
Irish Irish immigrants were despised.
Um you know they well all immigrants you
know have struggles but uh you know the
ones from Ireland [laughter] had
tremendous struggles. So yeah to have
someone of Irish descent uh get into the
White House I mean that again that was a
big step forward.
Oh yeah. I mean it wasn't that long
earlier where there was a huge amount of
discrimination against the Irish. You've
seen those signs, Irish need not apply.
>> No Irish needly, right? [laughter]
>> Yeah. And I was actually on a tour. I
couldn't believe this, but someone said
the Kennedys were Boston blueb
bloodoods. And I I [laughter]
immediately said, "No, if you were an
Irish Catholic in Boston, no matter how
wealthy you were, you were not a
blueblood."
>> No way.
No way.
>> Yeah. You could have a lot of money and
still be an outsider.
>> Yes. In those country clubs, you know,
if you were Jewish, if you had um if
you're Catholic, if you had certain
ethnic backgrounds, Irish, Italian, uh
they just didn't want you in there.
And then, of course, if you were
African-American, Asian-American, oh, it
was an absolute no. No, no.
All right, let's continue on. So then,
um, they took a motorcade through the
streets of San Antonio. And one of the
things that you I frequently hear people
say when we're talking about the
assassination, "Oh god, why did he drive
around with in that motorcade with the
top down? That was really unsafe." Well,
you know, that's really kind of like a
modern um perspective on things because
back then that was a common thing to do.
People did it all the time, including
him. So, just um I'll give you some
examples. So, here he is riding through
the streets of San Antonio in the uh
presidential limousine. And if you're
familiar with San Antonio, uh this is
actually right off of Broadway Street in
Alamo Heights. If you want to go check
this out, I love the guy standing on the
back of his truck photobombing uh this.
And this was in front of a school. And
so the children lined the sides of the
street and were waving to the motorcade.
And then they put up a historical marker
here. um a few years ago. So again, this
is in um San Antonio. It's on Broadway.
It's like, if you're familiar with San
Antonio, it's um north of Central
Market, uh if you know where that is,
actually by like I don't know, a mile or
two, not very far away. Um and then this
is cool. When they put up the um
historical marker, this guy uh he was a
child at this school and he's pointing
out to his family uh where he is in the
photo. So that's really neat. So you can
go check that out if you're in San
Antonio. Uh, and again, I bet if you
surveyed people in San Antonio, uh, a
lot of them would not know that
President Kennedy visited there, just
like same thing in Houston and Fort
Worth. Um, they actually published the
motorcade route in the paper. Uh, they
did the same thing in Dallas, which a
lot of people find shocking, but it
wasn't a, um,
you know, wasn't an uncommon thing to
do. I mean, they wanted people to come
out and see them. Um, that was, you
know, part of the deal. Here's San
Antonio International Airport. So they
took a motorcade from here down to here
and they were going to Brooks Air Force
Base where a aerospace medical center uh
was being dedicated and President
Kennedy was going to speak there. Then
they took the motorcade on another uh
quick trip and he flew out of Kelly Air
Force Base. Uh reason he flew out of one
and spoke at a different one is just
again chance to interact with the
people.
And again, here's that photo,
famous photo of his time in San Antonio.
And they're cruising around the streets
of San Antonio. That's downtown San
Antonio if you don't recognize it,
the Alamo City,
home of the San Antonio Spurs. And you
know there, look at the motorcade. So,
um, now this doesn't have President uh
the this is the the followup. This is
like the rear of the motorcade. The
president's limousine is up front. But I
mean, you can look at this. If somebody
wanted to do something, it would be
pretty easy just to walk out onto the
street or pop out of one of these
windows. So, I'm just kind of showing
you again to kind of give you the
context that the trip to Dallas and the
motorcade, that was not an unusual
thing. And it wasn't just Kennedy. Other
presidents, especially Eisenhower, had
done a lot of things like this before as
well. So, it was just kind of a
different era. I mean, look at all these
people, uh, you know, sticking out of
the upstairs balcony,
cruising through the streets,
and you know, here he is right here. And
here's Jackie
and Secret Service right behind him. And
then look at all this big giant
motorcade of press and secret service
and buses and etc.
And here they are cruising through
downtown.
And then okay, so then they get to the
Air Force base and President Kenny is
going to deliver a short speech. You can
actually find um it on YouTube if you're
interested in listening to it.
And here's Lyndon Johnson, who in about
24 hours is going to be president with
Jackie.
It's funny in this picture, it looks
like he's holding his iPhone, doesn't
it?
>> Yes, it does.
>> The light blue cover. Hey, Jackie, let's
take a selfie. [laughter]
I'll text it to you. I'll tag you.
>> Um, let's see. And [clears throat]
here's the two of them.
She looks so happy. He looks so happy.
Everyone looks happy.
And again, this is kind of the myth is
he went down there and everyone hated
him and there was a lot of division. I'm
not saying there wasn't some of that.
Um, but there was also a lot of, you
know, happiness and joy and stuff as
well. So, it's not all one or the other
usually in historical situations. Um,
let's see. So, then he ends up giving
this speech, dedication speech again to
the Brooks Aerospace Medical Division.
It was a nice speech. Um,
>> Ladybird was
>> Yeah. Um, I'll play a clip from the
speech um, a little bit later. Then they
get in the car and they drive through
the motorcade onto the next Air Force
base. I don't have any pictures of that
particular leg of the trip. Um, but here
they are showing up. And then, okay, so
here's the press coverage the next day.
Thousands give JFK rousing San Antonio
welcome. And there's pictures of him
with this big crowd of people. So, that
looks like a successful trip or visit.
Um, let's see. And then, okay, up in
Dallas where he's going to be the next
day. What were they saying about the San
Antonio visit? Plea for space plan kicks
off JFK tour. President Dy's economic
drain, etc. Ironically enough, Richard
Nixon was in Dallas right before
President Kennedy.
And then later on the day they end up
going to Houston and again this is kind
of another forgotten part of the story.
Um so here they are landing on Air Force
One departing the plane. You can tell
the Houston pictures because it's a
little bit later in the day. So you can
see the sun is going down. Has a little
different type of um uh coloring so to
speak. And then here they are departing
the plane with the entourage so to speak
and being greeted by dignitaries.
They're still wearing their same
outfits. Now, notice Jackie gets yellow
roses. Yellow roses are one of the
flowers of Texas. And in Dallas, she got
red roses, which we'll talk about that a
little bit later.
And again, looking very happy. The hand
shaking, the gloves, the sun coming down
or going down.
Yeah, I just have a com I'm reading some
of the comments and they said that uh
some people say JFK was not the first
American president of Irish ancestry
although he was definitely the first
Catholic one. Uh yeah, I think there are
some presidents who ancestors came from
Northern Ireland. You they're called
ScotsIrish, Irish Protestant and um
yeah, it just shows the complexity of
Irish history. Well, he was a Wasn't he
100% Irish or at least 50% Irish? I
mean, yeah,
>> he was Yeah, it was 100 proof.
[laughter]
>> There were some There were some people
that had Irish ancestry, but not to the
extent that he did.
>> And they were Irish on both sides. He
was
>> Yeah, his mother was his father.
>> His mother was
a political
Honey Fitz um Fitzgerald um was
[laughter] a Boston.
So,
[clears throat]
>> okay.
>> No, I think there were some presidents
before whose ancestors came from
Northern Ireland and, you know, that was
the the um, you know, heavily Protestant
and just culturally different from
southern Ireland. Again, you know, every
ethnic group has its complexities.
Part of what changed it was the potato
famine when Irish people immigrated
um into the United States. So um yeah,
that was part of it. Um it changed the
older people had some Irish roots, but
again that was when everybody it all all
the white people in America were
immigrants. Okay. Even around the time
of the was still so yes it was a
different timing. It wasn't just about
the Irishness. It was about the Irish
roots that and that were very political
because one of the ways the Irish worked
their way into American life was through
political activity.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Andrew Jackson. Yeah. He was of
Irish ancestry. Of course, they always
told me Scott's Irish. And yes, it's the
Republic of Ireland, not Southern
Ireland.
>> Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Let's continue on.
We're getting kind of sidetracked from
Irish ancestry. Um, all good. No, I
appreciate that. But let's continue on
because we have a lot of other stuff to
cover. I don't want to go off too much
of a tangent on um that. So, again, big
crowd in Houston. Turns out to see
President Mrs. Kennedy and yeah, look at
all these people and waving and taking
pictures and all this stuff. So, they
got huge crowds uh everywhere they ended
up going. This is a really cute photo.
Look at the expression on President
Kennedy and Jacqueline Kennedy's faces.
I'm like, "Wow, look at all these people
coming out to see us."
>> Yeah, she has an almost cocketish
expression on her face.
>> What? What kind of expression, Patty?
>> Coetish, you know, like she like
delighted like an she's interacting with
the crowd. She looks delighted, not just
happy. She looks delighted.
>> Oh, yeah. Well, he looks happy, too. So,
that's nice. And again, they're they're
traveling together, so I'm sure that was
nice for him.
>> Um, and then again, these pictures are
interesting. Uh, also just because like
I said, the sun is going down, the
lighting is very different than the San
Antonio one. So when I look at pictures
of uh them myself, I can immediately
tell if it's at the San Antonio airport
or the Houston airport just because the
position of sun and then okay, so here
they are traveling through the motorcade
again through the city of Houston. Same
thing. They put the route in the paper.
There's all these people lining the
streets. Um, if you've ever driven in
Houston and you've seen that horrific
traffic, well, that's not something new
that's been [laughter] going on for
quite a while. Houston's Houston's known
for having uh some challenging traffic
situations, but hey, if you're the
presidential motorcade, they close the
streets in that direction. You don't
have to deal with that. Um, and then
here it is. So, I always think this is
cool when someone takes a This isn't my
photo or my hand, but people take
historical photos and they superimpose
them over the way things look now. And
so, here's the motorcade cruising
through downtown Houston.
And look at all these people let him
shoot. So, again, same thing. Someone
could have easily just had a gun in
their pocket or their coat and walked up
to his car and shot him at pretty much
point blank range. It was just a
different era back then. you would not
do anything um like this now, but back
then, you know, because you think about
it, nothing had really happened like
this before, at least not um in a
motorcade type situation. Um let's see.
And then Jackie gave this really cool
speech in Spanish. Of course, Texas has
a large uh Hispanic and Latino
population, a lot of Spanish speakers.
Um I'm not going to play it, but if you
interested, you can check it out on
YouTube. Um, Jackie spoke several
languages. So, really neat that she gave
her speech in Spanish.
And then here they are greeting the
crowd with some Spanish musicians in the
background.
And his speech um kind of centered on
economics. And then, like I said, she
gave her um speech as well. And they get
on the plane in Houston and they're off
to Fort Worth. So, wow, it's been a
really long day. Um, it's not even over
with yet. They land in Fort Worth really
late Thursday evening and they head out
Friday morning. And um I used to I used
to give tours in Fort Worth. I've kind
of had to put them on hiatus because
I've been so busy at work. But um I
can't tell you how many people that I've
met. Oh, I didn't know the Kennedys had
come to Fort Worth. Yeah. Not only did
they come, they were there the night
before the assassination. Um this is
what Joanne was referring to earlier.
They stayed at a place called the Hotel
Texas, which at the time was the
fanciest, most well-known uh hotel in
Fort Worth. It was kind of like be the
equivalent of like, I don't know, uh the
Willard in Washington DC or the um you
know, I don't know, the Histori in the
Waldorf Histori in New York or something
like that or the Driscoll in Austin, one
of those kind of like old money type of
places.
Um, and then here's a postcard of it
from back in the day.
And the Kennedy stayed in suite 1530,
which is the presidential suite. You can
actually still stay there. So, if you
want to go uh visit the hotel and you
can request the presidential suite. Now,
it's going to cost you a little bit of
money because it's very I'm kind of
bummed out. Um, I've never actually
really seen any good photos of the art
that was on display there. This is what
the room looks like now. And sorry, this
photo is actually even a little bit
blurry. Um, and then this is their
bedroom. So, this was the suite that
they stayed in. But Joanne, when you saw
the exhibition or the book, are there
any good photos of the art hanging up on
the walls? Because I've seen a couple,
but they were like really blurry and it
wasn't really it's kind of hard to look
at the art from the photos that I saw.
But what about your book?
Um I I think the book is very good and I
went to the exhibit itself and I was
very impressed.
>> Okay. Well, that's good to know. Um so
yeah, this is where the Kennedy spent
essentially their last night uh
together. Um because this is Thursday
evening and he was shot and killed on
Friday. So they spend their last night
together um as a married couple, husband
and wife, president, first lady in Fort
Worth, Texas.
And here's another image of the hotel.
Again, it's in downtown Fort Worth. And
so, here's the entrance. It's configured
a little bit differently now. This
parking lot um has been changed,
but what happened was they checked into
the hotel really late at night, so it
was a super long day for them. Um, and
then the next morning it was raining
out, but miraculously enough a ton of
people gathered outside of the hotel to
get a chance to see President andor Mrs.
Kennedy. And so, President Kennedy was
not planning on going outside to meet
the people or talk to them or do
anything, but his staff had told him
like, "Man, there's like a couple
thousand people outside
and and and in the rain, too. it was
drizzling. And so, uh, it was a side,
hey, maybe he should go out there and
make a few comments. Um, Fort Worth,
interestingly enough, is known as where
the west begins. And so, President Kenny
does that. He actually goes outside and
greets all these people that have been
standing in the drizzle uh, hoping to
see him andor his wife. And so, he gives
this impromptu speech. Um, it's the next
to last speech that he ever gave. It was
a impromptu thing. You can also find
versions of this on YouTube. I would I'd
love to play all these different
speeches for you that he gave during
this trip, but the program would end up
being way too long. But if you're
interested, um you can go check it out
on the internet. There he is with Je uh
Governor Connley of Texas and Vice
President Johnson, who of course also
was from Texas. Um and yeah, look at all
these people standing out in the
drizzle. You can see people with their
umbrellas and their raincoats on.
the rain had just stopped and so it was
kind of like a opening of clear weather.
He ends up going out there and then wow
look at this mass of people and again
same thing. Someone could have easily if
they wanted to do them harm uh done so
in this particular spot u but no one
did. Everyone was very well behaved.
And if you go to Fort Worth you can
actually visit the site where President
Kennedy gave this speech. They've turned
it into a memorial to President Kennedy.
They have the text of his speech here.
Uh this nice statue of him here. There's
a photo. You can't see it. It's
partially obscure, but it's Jackie. Um
and President Kennedy. And then here he
is giving the speech and then all the
crowd and all this kind of stuff. So
this is right in downtown Fort Worth. Um
if you want to go check this out, uh the
hotel is now the Hilton.
And there's some more pictures of the
memorial.
And I used to um
lead these tours of downtown for Worth.
Again, I apologize. I've had to take a
break. But um I can't tell. It's like
seems like half the people on the tour
have no idea this was here or um knew
that he gave the speech. But you know,
hey, no big deal. That's one reason why
we do these tours is so people can learn
um about their history. I'll let you
read that historical marker. again just
really fascinating that they spent their
last night together in Fort Worth and
like Joanne said about the artwork and
um all that kind of stuff. So um now the
reason why he was in Fort Worth, he was
giving a speech the next morning at the
Fort Worth Chamber of Commerce. So this
was like the official event. The speech
that he gave outside was an impromptu um
type of thing.
And this is the last speech that
President Kennedy gave. Um, and here's
how he ended up concluding the speech.
Um, and again, this is another speech
that you can find on the internet. I am
confident as I look to the future that
our chances for security, our chances
for peace are better than they have been
in the past. And the reason is because
we are stronger. And with that strength
is a determination to not only maintain
the peace, but also the vital interests
of the United States. To that great
cause, Texas and United States are
committed. Thank you. uh one reason why
he went to Fort Worth, it's
traditionally had a big defense industry
um in Fort Worth. And so he was kind of
coming to talk about uh American
military strength and the diplomatic um
advantages of being uh like say
negotiating from a position of strength.
So that was the purpose of the speech.
But again um delivering the speech at
the Fort Worth Chamber of Commerce, you
can see Jackie sitting over here, Lyndon
Johnson next door.
Um just to just an aside, um this is
taking place one year and one month
after the Cuban missile crisis and if
anybody remembers when you were showing
the graphs of his popularity that really
you could see a huge dip and then a big
rise. Um and that was occurring right
near the like end toward the end of '
62. That was regarding the missile
crisis actually.
>> Oh, thanks Patty. I really appreciate
you mentioning that because yeah, I
forgot to let me go back to that.
Tada. Here you are.
>> Yep. See how you've got that slope down
and then all of a sudden that big rise
up. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Great point, Patty.
Appreciate you mentioning that. Thank
you. Um, that's why I love having you
and Brad and also tonight Joanne here
chime in with things I didn't know or
forgot to mention. Uh, let's see. Going
back to Fort Worth.
Oh, was someone gonna say something?
No, I just want to say about the Cuban
missile crisis. Uh, and Matt, remember
the TV series Madmen. They did a great
episode about the Cuban Missile Crisis
and how people reacted. It was quite an
eye openener.
>> I remember that episode. A lot of great
episodes in Madmen, but I particularly
remember that one. Um, let's see. So,
yeah, here's Jackie and Lynden Johnson
and Lady Bird Johnson over here.
And then here they are departing the
Hotel Texas in Fort Worth.
We'll talk about her
>> question about the the graph. No, the
slump was leading up into the crisis in
the early part of the crisis. The jump
was after the crisis was over.
>> Somebody misunderstood that. Yeah.
[laughter]
>> Well, yeah, the approval rating too went
down. I mean, when someone goes into the
White House, they talk about the
honeymoon period where usually their
approval ratings are a little bit higher
as people kind of giving them the
benefit of the doubt or, you know,
optimistic about the future, then uh,
you know, continue on and maybe it goes
down. That's pretty much true for most
presidents. Um, again, welcome to Fort
Worth, Texas. There's a W missing here,
but where the West begins, uh, here's
Jackie coming out with her pink Chanel
suit and President Kennedy following
behind her.
And okay, now we're going to cruise
through the streets of Fort Worth. And
wow, look at all these people. This is
downtown Fort Worth, Texas. And same
thing. So, another huge crowd of people.
And again, I think maybe these pictures
might um we were talking before about,
you know, the assassination fact versus
fiction and oh yeah, there was all this
division and people hated them and
stuff. Yeah, they did a certain degree,
but not everybody thought that way. Uh
look at all these people out here. So,
this is a really cool photo. um seeing
him walking through downtown Fort Worth.
Oh, so we've been recording this. All
right, so we were talking about the fact
that this was a three-day trip. Um so
one of the things that's kind of
interesting, maybe if you're not
familiar with North Texas, he they were
in Fort Worth and they actually flew to
Dallas. Um they flew from Fort Worth to
Dallas, which not many people do. Why
would they do that? It's not very far
away. Well, the one thing, the traffic
can be bad. Number two, they were
actually leaving there and going to
Austin. So, if they would have driven
from Fort Worth to Dallas, which is only
like a 10-minute flight, uh they would
have had to turn around and drive all
the way back to Fort Worth to fly out
from there. So, when they landed in Fort
Worth, the plane was there, but then
after he gave that speech to the Chamber
of Commerce, they ended up flying to
Dallas and they land at Love Field. So,
they didn't drive from Fort Worth to
Dallas. They ended up driving. Um, and
here he is departing Fort Worth,
waving goodbye to the crowd. And then he
arrives in Dallas. And so, here's a
timeline. Um, the timeline, it'll extend
on to the bottom of the page. Um, I'll
show that at a little bit later. If you
wanted to take like a picture of it, a
screenshot, you're more than welcome to,
but you might want to wait till I
actually show the whole entire thing.
So, uh, 11:38 a.m. Air Force One lands
at Lovefield in Dallas. Uh, they were
stayed there for about 14 minutes and
then the motorcade left field, which is,
um, it's the original airport in Dallas.
Now, they also have Dallas Fort Worth
airport. Uh, and then at 12:30,
President Kennedy was shot. So he was
only in Dallas for a short time, less
than an hour from the time the plane
went until he was shot. And there are
some protesters um here just like there
were in other places that the president
visited throughout his administration,
but there's also a lot of supporters. Um
you can see this big crowd of people and
again maybe a little bit dispelling the
myth that oh everyone was very hostile
and he was going into enemy territory so
to speak. Um, here's the Dallas Morning
News. The morning of the assassination,
storm of political controversy swirls
around Kennedy on visit. Um, I do see
that, but I also think maybe this is
the, you know, media kind of stirring up
a little bit of stuff. Uh, Yarborough
snubs LBJ. And then if you look down
here closely, here's the motorcade
route, which we had seen that before.
Um, so this is how Oswald finds out
where Kennedy's going.
they are. And there's that
motorcade route, front page of the
paper. And again, they're doing the
motorcade because they want people to
come out. So, it's not like it was a
secret where he was going. Um, that was
part of the problem. Um, but yeah, there
were some people that were not happy
with President Kennedy. There's never
been any president ever and probably
never will be that did have people that
um are against them. That's just the way
it goes. Um, as he used to say at
church, even Jesus had his distractors.
Um, so they were distributing these
wanted posters and people were
protesting and stuff. So yeah, there was
some of that as well. I don't want to I
don't want to diminish that, make it
seem like everyone there loved him. That
wasn't the case either. Um, and here
they are departing the plane. This is
one of the more famous photos of the
Dallas trip. And it's a bright sunny
day. Now, remember earlier it was
drizzling in Fort Worth and if that
weather had stayed that way, he wouldn't
have been driving around in the
convertible. So, that's kind of an
interesting uh what if. It was also
really warm this day. Um I forget what
year it was. I think it was two years
ago. I gave the tour uh the in-person
tour of the Kennedy assassination in
downtown Dallas. And holy cow, it was
freezing out. It was like I don't know
[laughter] 40° and it was like super
windy and we were talking about that
like man if they would have had weather
like this the day [laughter] he was in
Dallas uh you know he would have lived
they would have been driving around in a
convertible so but it was warm this
what's that Brad and Joy
>> they would have put the bubble top on
top of the car
>> uh it's typical Texas weather except in
the summertime
>> yeah it can really vary a lot
>> volatile I mean one day is summery The
next day we're in Snowageddon.
>> Well, yeah. It was funny because that
was in um 20 23 I think it was really
cold. Well, then the next year it was
the exact opposite. It was like
incredibly hot walking around and people
were like, "OH MY GOD, HOW MUCH FURTHER
DO WE HAVE TO WALK? IT'S like 95 degrees
out." So, you just never know in Texas.
Um but anyway, a famous photo of the two
of them departing Air Force One. Um and
then, okay, here she is. She's the woman
standing there with the yellow flowers.
Then this woman has red roses. So what
happened was there was so much um kind
of euphoria of the Kennedys coming to
North Texas.
>> They florists ran out of yellow flowers.
And so they were uh you know scouring
the uh the metro area looking for yellow
roses, but they actually ran out. And so
they they wanted to give her some things
like we'll give her these red roses
instead. Better than nothing. Um but
kind of an ironic moment and she
actually Jackie later on would talk um
about that but here she is holding the
red roses. So kind of an um ironic twist
of fate. Um again really nice weather
very contrast with the morning in Fort
Worth when it was raining uh when he
came out of the hotel for the speech.
And then here's a quote from Jackie a
little bit later on in an interview she
gave uh speaking about her trip to Texas
and the flowers. Every time we got off
the plane that day, three times they
she's actually referring to the previous
day as well, though. Um, three times
they gave me the yellow roses of Texas.
So, San Antonio, Houston, Fort Worth,
but in Dallas they gave me red roses. I
[clears throat] thought, how funny, red
roses. So, all the seat was full of
blood and red roses, meaning after the
assassination. So, kind of an ironic
twist of fate there.
Um, and then the pink Chanel suit, which
is super famous. Made of wool, the
double- breasted raspberry pink and navy
trim collared suit was matched with the
trademark matching pink pillbox hat and
white gloves. In the early 1960s, the
Chanel suit was a wardrobe staple of the
upwardly mobile American female. It
evoked a powerful image of
sophisticated, intelligent, and
independent modern woman and could fit
almost every daytime occasion that
required a woman to dress stylishly.
Given that the Chanel suit was a strong
statement of an independent woman, it is
balanced by the color pink which has an
element of traditional femininity. So,
it's kind of interesting the the
contrast between those two different
ideas. And you know what? Before I
started studying the assassination, I
didn't really know all the um historical
context of this suit, but really
interesting. uh most of the American
public viewing pictures of the
presidential couple on television and
even in newspapers and magazines would
not have known the color of the pink
suit given that at the time TV news and
newspapers were predominantly in black
and white. The color of the suit did not
become widely known until the
publication of color photos in Life
magazine's JFK Memorial issue November
29th, 1963. So 7 days after. Um, so
that's an interesting tidbit as well.
Eventually the suit, which was never
cleaned, was given to the National
Archives. It will not be seen by the
public until at least 21103.
Um, that's kind of a whole another
tangent story about family and privacy
and all that stuff, but you think about
it. Can you think of any more iconic
clothing item in American history? Hm. I
don't know. Um, so anyway, that's the
pink Chanel suit. Um, Patty, Brad,
Joanne, any thoughts on the suit or
anything related to the arrival in
Dallas?
One of the reasons that this the style
was such a sensation is that it has it
it's the top the jacket sort of ends at
the waist. And if you think of a
traditional suit jacket,
>> it would be more like a a man's suit
jacket which would have the lapels and
the you know the thing coming down to
hip level. So that
>> Oh, I was going to say let me show you
some pictures. Let's come back to that.
So this wasn't the first time that
Jackie had worn that suit. Um, here she
is at a public event where they were um
announcing the renovation of Lafayette
Square, which is across the street from
White House, which is also a very
interesting event, but we don't um have
time to get on that. But yeah, here's
the suit. So, um, Patty wanted to show
the pictures that you were um referring
to. And then here's a um like a fashion
magazine that has a model uh wearing the
same suit. Now, unfortunately, it's not
colored. Um, so now repeat that again,
Patty, about the the jacket.
>> Well, instead of a traditional suit
jacket and you actually see them more
often now, it would come down to below
like the the hip um and and curve away,
whereas the Chanel
>> ended on a straight line right just
maybe slightly below the waist. But so
it implied that feminine shape
underneath that boxy looking suit. It it
it's an interesting it's almost like a
Trumpoy
um
effect because it it makes you see the
feminine shape even as you're looking at
something that is actually very boxy. It
it's hard to explain unless you put it
next to a traditional, you know, suit
skirt and jacket.
>> Okay. Well, thanks. I'll have to do that
um for next time. What about Brad and
>> I I heard, don't quote me on this, but I
actually heard that that was an imit
that suit was not actually designed by
Chanel. It was an imitation of a Chanel
suit.
>> Okay. Well, I guess called Chanel
Chanel Coco Chanel,
>> but Chanel um no, of course, you know,
Chanel, that great fashion designer, she
she had her complications, but um when
she designed and marketed the suits in
France, they were considered rather
dated, but they were very, very popular
in America.
>> Yeah. And of course, Jackie likes all
things French.
>> Yes. He was a French literature major in
college and spoke French and was
familiar with and had gone to school
actually in Paris for several months
when she was at college. So
>> take a tour in Paris. You can take a
tour of um the apartment where she
lived.
>> Oh, really? Oh, I didn't know that.
That's interesting. [snorts]
>> Um let's see. All right. Anything else
on the arrival to Dallas?
>> All right. Well, let's continue on. So
again, she had worn the um pink suit
before. I think if I'm not mistaken, she
wore it two or three or four times. This
wasn't this um Lafayette Square um thing
wasn't the only time she'd worn it
before. Um so that's interesting in
itself. And then
some great photos. So um yeah, all the
people coming out to the airport. Again,
this is Dallas Love Field. I actually
have not flown out of Dallas Fort or
Dallas Love Field in a long, long time.
And I'm not sure if they have like a
historical marker there signifying um
the events that took place. Maybe
someone that might be familiar with the
airport can uh let me know in the chat
if that's actually something that they
do or not. I forgot to look that up.
And again, all smiles.
And you know, this is less than an hour
before he's going to be shot and killed,
just to give you that context.
And then uh yeah, a big mass of people.
So it's hard to see the candies in this
big crowd. There's a fence here. And so
what's happened is they've come over to
shake hands of all the people in this
fence. So here's President Kennedy, the
blue arrow. Here's Jackie with the pink
arrow and the flower. And of course, you
know, you got to have a Confederate
flag. Texas along with the Texas flag,
which as a non- Texan that moved here, I
think it's interesting how often you see
the Texas state flag around the state of
the in my opinion, you see it you see
the Texas state flag more in than any
other state flag in the US. Um,
>> Jan is just answering your question.
Let's see. Jan Paulson is saying,
>> "Yes, there is a marker in field."
>> Okay. That commemorates where Lyn B.
Johnson was sworn in as president after
JFK's assassination, but no marker for
JFK himself at the field. Interesting.
>> Oh, now that Yeah, that is interesting.
Well, thanks, Jan. Um, I appreciate
that. I almost feel like I should uh
book a flight out of field to go check
it out and research it. Um, again,
here's all the media and the people
coming out to see them and the
handshakes and all that stuff.
And then this is where he was headed to.
So, he was going to the Dallas trademark
to deliver a speech. Look at all those
cool cars in the parking lot. This is
actually a photo, not from the day of
the assassination, but just a historical
photo. Um, but this was the destination
in Dallas. He's flying in there to give
this speech at the Dallas trademark. It
was a economic type speech. Um, and he's
taking this motorcade from Love Field to
the Trademark. And then this is the
trademark. They set this up um in
anticipation of the Kennedy's arrival.
And this was a big event. I can't
remember off the top of my head how many
people were attending this, but it was a
lot. This is a really big um uh building
and it can hold a lot of people. And so
there was many, many people that were
going to be listening to him speak. And
of course, Dallas um even back then was
a big city
>> and most of them were there at the time
all the events of the assassination
happened. This is where they learned
about what was going on.
>> Oh yeah, thanks for mentioning that,
Patty, because I forgot to include that.
Yeah, I mean that figure he was shot
just minutes before he was supposed to
show up at the uh this venue. So the
people are already there uh waiting for
him to arrive when the news shows up.
And then after the trademark speech,
what was supposed to happen? He was he
was supposed to drive back to Lovefield,
get on the airplane, and then fly down
to Austin and he was going to give a
speech at the convention center. And you
can see the sign um over on the left,
welcome President John F. Kennedy. Now,
of course, he never made it there. And
then after that speech, they were going
to head out to the Lynden Baines Johnson
ranch and they were going to have a
barbecue and they were going to spend
the night and then they were going to
fly back to Washington DC the next
morning, Saturday morning. So that was
the plan. Um it didn't quite work out
that way. So let's talk about the
motorcade. Uh here's President Kennedy.
They've gotten in the limousine. They've
decided to drop the top. Uh we'll talk
about the car in just a moment. There's
Jackie and then the red roses in the
center and that's Governor Connley.
And so the presidential car was a blue
presidential blue metallic 1961 Lincoln
Continental. It looks black in a lot of
photos, but it's actually kind of like a
bluish black. Um, but there was three
different ways they could operate it.
They could use it as a convertible. As
Brad was mentioning earlier, they had a
bubble top that they could put on it um
to kind of allow the president to see
and be seen, but kind of protect him
from the elements, so to speak. And then
they could be used as a hard top. And it
was decided because the weather had
warmed up and gotten sunny that they
would use it as a convertible in this
particular instance.
And the car is on display at Henry Ford
Museum in Dearborn. We'll talk about
that a little bit later. Um, again, it
was not uncommon for um, President and
Mrs. Kennedy to travel around and open
cars and motorcades. Um, I always think
this is a cute photo of the two of them.
You know, again, going back to the, oh,
they had a terrible marriage and she was
suffering. Not saying there wasn't, um,
some of that, but when you see pictures
of her, um, you know, she's frequently
smiling in public. Now, this was before
he was elected president, FYI. Um, but
again, it was common for them to travel
um, in open cars. It was just kind of a
thing that people did uh back then. This
is when he was a senator before he was
president. And then this is during the
um presidential campaign. Jackie's got a
super excited look on her face.
>> Another thing that I think gets lost is
that he was like the most eligible
bachelor in Washington uh long before he
met Jacqueline. And he did choose her. I
I think and they chose each other. I
believe she was engaged or almost
engaged when she first met him.
>> Yeah, she was engaged and she broke off
the engage. Not because of him, but just
in
>> Yeah. You can never understand other
people's relationships and it's really
a, you know, a loser's game to try to.
But there was a reason why they were
together and there were probably more
than one reason. But um they were a
complex couple and they had they offered
each other a lot but there was not a
perfect relationship. And you tell me
who has a perfect relationship. So
>> I mean I do but I realize not everyone's
as lucky to be married to some amazing
person like Michelle but you know hey
that's just the way it goes. But you
know mine is
>> but uh well no I um there and of course
you have to take into consideration you
know the times they were living in uh
that certainly doesn't excuse all his in
my god his infidelities his numerous
infidelities
but uh you know you it's um
>> Oh yeah no that's true.
>> I think they I think they had a certain
bond but there were so many problem so
many problems that got in the way. Oh,
yeah. No, that's true. I mean, that
that's like a whole another um
[laughter] topic. I don't want this to
be the JFK assassination tour, not the
JFK infidelity. [laughter]
>> I just find it painful when these
programs devolve into like almost
exclusively cynical comments because it
tends to obscure the actual events that
were happening and the complexity of it.
And I don't know, to me, cynicism has
never accomplished anything great.
[laughter]
>> Oh, yeah. No, that's true. I mean it I
mean I mean the one hand they are like
so couple and multifas but I mean at the
end of the day this is the topic for
tonight. It's trying to stay focused on
this and not go too far off on a
tangent. Although you know again they're
fascinating people and he was the
president and she was the first lady and
um all these different facets to him. So
but you know what we'll save some of
those for a future day. know from this
that they didn't end their marriage by
divorce or any of the other things.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Mr. Oswald took care of that.
[laughter]
>> Um but I I love this photo. It's like
well you know she looks really happy in
this picture.
>> Now granted this was before
>> it I think it's very it's very difficult
to find that sweet spot between this you
know excuse. Well, it was just they were
just um creatures of their era, their
time. But then uh there's the opposite
extreme of attacking them.
>> Um it's very difficult to find that you
that middle that balance. No one has
done it.
>> Oh yeah. No, very true. Um but anyway,
the reason why I was showing these
photos just it was common for them to be
riding in open cars whether they were
campaigning or parades and even after he
was president. Now, these are all photos
from before um he was president. Um
including this one as well. This
particular photo, Jackie is actually pre
pregnant with John Jr.
>> I don't think I've ever seen another
photo of her wearing purple. [laughter]
>> Oh, really? Oh, that's interesting.
>> It's not her best color either if you
look at that. [laughter]
>> Oh, I don't know. I like that. I like
that color on her, but I also like
purple. Um okay, so then this is their
inauguration. They're riding in an open
car.
And then this photo was actually taken
in downtown Washington DC. This is
actually just a few weeks before the
assassination. I don't remember the
exact date um of this photo, but you can
see he's riding in a motorcade. Look,
this look this he he's actually standing
up in this photo. He would have been an
easier target um so to speak in this
particular instance.
>> That might be Salassie of Ethiopia in
the car with him.
>> That's a
>> Oh, yeah. does look a lot like him.
>> Um, let's see. And then
>> um Jackie and her sister went to India.
Now, President Kennedy didn't accompany
her. It was a solo trip, but even there
she's by herself and not without not
with her husband. I mean, um, and look,
even she's riding around in an open car
um in another country of all places. Um,
so this is India. Jackie took this very
famous trip to India.
>> Yes, Jackie was a Jackie was a natural
ambassador. Uh Caroline certainly
inherited those talents and I think it
was just much more naive time.
>> Oh yeah, a different different era as
well. Um here they are traveling through
Mexico. Um I know one be like, "Oh god,
Mexico." Um well, you know, he's driving
through here, open car, nothing
happened.
>> [clears throat]
>> Um, again, different era, but oh, look
at all the people that came out. And
then here's a photo. He President Kenny
famously took a trip back to Ireland and
of course the locals went crazy there
because of his Irish ancestors. But same
thing, he's riding around a car. So, you
know, the point being with all these
photos is the motorcade through Dallas
in the convertible was not like a unique
uh one-time event because you'll see
hear people say all that, oh, why was he
in the motorcade with the convertible
top down? That was crazy. Well, it was
just something that people did back
then. was really common. You can even
see the people out here um you know
looking out the windows and stuff. So uh
even in foreign countries uh it was safe
to do so.
>> And if you really if you really think
about it, I mean if if there's anything
else all of these series of pictures
drives home,
there is no way that Secret Service men
on the ground can actually protect any
one given person in these types of
situations. Oh, that's an excellent
point, Patty. Thanks for mentioning
that. Yeah, I mean, they can only do so
much.
>> That's why they so far the other way
with all the later presidents.
>> I mean, they they learned a lot from
this.
And I don't think there'll ever be a
bubble top or non bulletproof limousine
for the president again.
>> Oh, yeah. And it's a very different era.
Yeah. I mean now things are much more um
controlled but you know they have to be
that there's there's been no presidents
assassinated since Kennedy but there's
been numerous close calls um you know
Reagan and Ford and I mean he wasn't
present time but even uh Donald Trump
and so yeah it's just we live in a
crazier era um unfortunately
>> um let's see all right let me queue up
some more videos I got to pause the
recording
>> was that Mrs. Connelly that said that or
>> Yes. Yeah. No Connelly.
>> That's what I thought. Yeah.
>> Um so again, this is um President
Kennedy driving through downtown Dallas.
This is Main Street. Uh the motorcade,
all the people. It's a bright, beautiful
day, warm weather. Um this is one of the
more famous photos of the Kennedy. This
is just moments before he was shot. Um
you can see motorcycle uh police right
there, all the people standing along the
street. This is Clint Hill. We'll talk
about him a little bit later in his
courageous acted
by the same photo. So you can see
President Kennedy, Mrs. Kennedy, uh,
Governor Connley, Mrs. Connley, and then
Secret Service drivers with
Secret Service behind them.
>> And then again, here's Clint Hills. So
he was the guy who ran up to the car and
jumped on board. We'll talk about that
in just a moment. Look at all the
smiling people.
And then this is one of the last photos
taken before the actual assassination.
Jackie's got a big smile on her face.
Even President Kennedy smiling. Um and
of course he was shot and killed by Lee
Harvey Oswald. Now there's a lot of
conspiracy theories of Ray of the
Kennedy. Um I'll be perfectly frank with
you. I don't believe any of the
conspiracy theories and uh I've
researched this case a lot and I think
the people that re that are into the
conspiracy theories. They tend to kind
of forget about or exclude a lot of
facts and I don't really want to go off
in that whole tangent because you could
do a separate program. I was thinking
maybe someday I'd do a program about why
I don't believe the any of the
conspiracy theorists but I want to save
that for another day. I don't want to
get distracted and give that credence
because um I actually think it's kind of
disrespectful um to President Kenny. But
you know what? If someone has a
different opinion, um, they're totally
entitled to it. Um, this is where he was
shot. The building is called the Book
Depository. Um, so what happened was the
presidential motorcade traveling down
the street here. They end up making a
left turn and Oswald is up here on the
sixth floor of the book depository. He
fires three shots. If you believe in the
Warren Commission, which I do, if again,
if you don't, that's totally fine, but
we'll save that debate for another day.
Um, here's the building in more modern
times. And so the motorcade traveled
down the street here right towards the
building and then they made a left turn.
And when they made the left turn is when
President Kennedy was shot. And this is
the window that Oswald was perched from.
This was the Texas school book
depository. So the Texas um school
system would store the textbooks that
they would use um and distribute to the
school. So they would be shipped from
the publishers to this book depository.
They'd be stored here and then they'd be
shipped out to the schools from there.
And Lee Harvey Oswald got a job working
here.
And then this is the view from the
window of the depository. So this would
have been Oswald's view. Um the
motorcade traveling down this street
here where the arrow is. They make a
left turn. This is Houston Street. Uh
they make a left turn onto Elm Street
and right along here is when where
President Kenny was shot. the trees was
tall back then, so he wouldn't have had
that obscured view.
>> And I think it was theorized that he
actually because the route was so well
published that he chose that particular
spot because it gave him the longest
view
um into the motorcade um from that
particular point.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. And he's on a top floor
and he's high up. Um
>> down the approach street and then you've
still got the the space going toward the
uh trademark.
>> Yeah. Um so the motorcade traveled down
here, made a right turn. Um so he
Oswald's working in this building, so it
was really convenient for him. I mean,
if he was working over here or over
here, um you know, history probably
would have turned out differently. Um
and the three red blocks are where
President Kennedy was shot.
And then
>> yes, it was because he worked there, but
that's the window that gave him the
largest amount of view. Yes. Oh my gosh.
>> Um, let's see. So, this is a picture
that was taken after the assassination.
So, there was already a lot of people
that were out um to view the motorcade,
but then after the shooting, a lot of
people that were curious, wanted to know
what's going on came to the site. Um,
it's got this big Chevrolet uh advertise
in the background. Here's the window
that he shot from.
And again, that photo that we saw
before. So, you can see President
Kennedy um is a very easy target. No, I
always kind of wonder like what would
have happened if they would have
switched seats. Um you know, would that
have impacted anything? Who knows? Um
and then this is one of the last photos
taken before he was shot.
And again, here's Clint Hill. We'll talk
about him in just a minute. Here's
President Kennedy's car.
And this is like a second before the
shooting started. And you can see Jackie
just happens to look over to the left.
And if you're interested in the grassy
null, that's like over here to the left
out of the picture.
And then here's the motorcade. Um, so
Zaprder
is, let's see, standing right here. You
can't see him because of the sign. Um,
this is what's known as the grassy null.
And here is Clint Hill. And of course,
here's Jaclyn Kennedy and here's
President Kennedy right here.
And then here's another view.
So, this is the view that Zaprruder
would have had. Um, there's a hill right
here. Uh, and you know, it's really
eerie to go to this site and actually
see this because so many people have
seen the Zaprruder film. Um, to actually
stand in that spot where we've watched
this video um that was taken is really
um an eerie kind of experience.
Um, so here's Abraham Zapruder. He's the
guy that famously took the home video of
the President Kennedy assassination. He
was um the owner and manager of a
clothing company that was located in the
building across the street from the Book
Depository. And he had just bought um
this camera and the video camera which
was a pretty much a novelty back then.
It was a bell & how
purchased the same type of camera. I saw
one for sale on eBay and I bought it and
um I bring it when I um give my
in-person tours and people are really
amazed like number one how heavy it is.
It we I don't know the weight but it
weighs a lot and the viewfinder is
really tiny. Um so people have really
enjoyed um looking through that. It's
interesting but next time I do the
inerson tour I'll be sure to bring it
again. The Zaprruder film is a silent 8
millimeter color motion picture sequence
shot by Abraham Zapruder with a Bell &
Howell home movie camera as United
States President John F. Kennedy's
motorcade passed through Daily Plaza in
Dallas, Texas on November 26th, 1963.
Unexpectedly ended up capturing the
president's assassination which was
really interesting displayed in the
movie Parkland. Um, even though it is
not the only film of the shooting, the
Zapruder film is considered to be the
most complete one, giving a relatively
clear view from a somewhat elevated
position on the side from which the
president's fatal head wound is visible.
It was an important part of the Warren
Commission hearings and all the
subsequent investigations of the
assassination, and it is one of the most
studied pieces of film in history. Um,
if you're interested, I'm actually going
to show the Zruder film uh a little bit
later if you're watching us live. Um,
but we'll do that a little bit later.
Here's an advertisement for the camera.
Again, it really weighs a lot. I don't
know the exact weight, but it's pretty
heavy. It's not like something you can
just stick in your pocket. Um, and
>> technology weighed a whole lot more back
then. [laughter]
>> Yeah, technology. Yeah, great point,
Patty. Technology weighed a whole lot
more um back then. And let's see.
And then again, this is an illustration.
So, the motorcade travels down here.
They turn left. So here's the pruder. So
he couldn't have picked a better spot um
to capture the event. So kind of ironic
of all the places he just ended up being
there. And I've often kind of also
wondered too how would the Kennedy um
assassination be say perceived or
interpreted if it wasn't um captured on
this video? Who knows? And again, we
talked about that Kennedy's the first
modern first couple, including even the
death of President Kennedy um captured
on video and televised. So, kind of
interesting. Now, it wasn't live
broadcast, of course, the video of the
shooting because uh Zaprder was a
private individual. The video didn't
come out till much much later. Um these
are stills of the video which I'll show
a little bit later if you're interested
in seeing that. Although I have to a
little bit graphic. What's that Patty?
If I remember correctly, um, yeah, there
was a great deal of discussion even
among the Life magazine people at the
time. And I think the first time they
published it, they left out a couple of,
um, frames.
>> Yeah, they left out the goriest part.
Um,
>> yeah,
>> of the frames. Good point. Which kind of
helped contribute to the conspiracy
theories. Now, um, again, I don't want
to get off in the conspiracy theory
thing, but one thing some people
theorize that maybe he was also shot in
the grassy null. This is where that area
is. So, it would have been like a
frontal um type of shot. This at this
point in time, President Kenny's already
been shot, but if you kind of picture
the motorcade being over here to the
right. Um, so that's what the infamous
Grassy Null is. Um, and then here's
heroic Clint Hill. So, he's a Secret
Service guy. He's standing on the riding
board of the car behind and when he
hears the shots go off, he immediately
springs to action. Now, this was
extremely dangerous on his part. First
of all, he's wearing a suit and dress
shoes. He jumps off the car behind uh
President Kennedy's um presidential
limousine and races at full speed up and
jumps on the back of the car, which that
was extremely dangerous. He could have
just one thing, the fact that he had the
wherewithal to act so quickly is
incredible. Number one. Number two, the
fact that he was in his suit and dress
shoes able to catch up to the car which
was moving. Um I mean, imagine running
up to a car that's driving down the
road. Now granted, it wasn't going 55
miles an hour, but that being said,
still quite an achievement. And number
three, had he fallen off the car, he
would have been run over by the car
behind him. So, he really risks his life
um to intervene in this situation. And
you know, at this point in time, uh no
one knew the extent of the shooting. Uh
here's a picture of him sliding into the
back seat. So, his uh objective here is
to protect the president and first lady
from any potential shooting. you know,
no one knows how many shooters there are
or what's going on, but really
incredible that he springs in action.
So, uh, really one of the more
interesting stories of the Kennedy
assassination. Clint Hill, he actually
just passed away a few months ago. He
wrote a number of books, uh, was a very
accomplished speaker. So, um, probably
do a whole program just on his, uh, life
and career, which was really, uh,
fascinating in that regard. Um,
>> if you think about it, if he had been
dressed in anything other than a dark
suit and um dress shoes, he would have
stood out and everybody would have known
who the Secret Service guys were.
[laughter]
>> Exactly. Um, and then here's kind of the
photo of, you know, transposed over the
way it looks uh, in modern times. The
Zapruder film was shot um, say over here
to the right of the screen. And then
let's see. If you go to Dallas again,
it's really eerie to stand on the spot
where Zaprruder took the film um just
because people have seen it and are so
familiar with it. They actually have X's
on the street uh where the bullet struck
Kennedy. That's kind of an unusual
feature especially when you see people
This is a actually a really busy street
and you'll see people out here like
standing taking pictures of stuff and
I'm always really super nervous when I
see it like oh my god [laughter]
my car. Um because it's, you know, it's
a busy street. There's traffic going
through. I hear Joanne laughing. You
know, [laughter]
>> it's like, God, you're gonna get Yeah.
man or woman killed, you know, in front
of Kennedy assassination spot trying to
take selfie or something, run over by
truck or whatever. Um, so that's crazy.
And then this is right after the
assassination. So these people heard the
gunshots. They're ducking for cover. Uh,
the people with the cameras are trying
to record what's going on. the police
and motor the as soon as the um um
shooting took place, the motorcade sped
up because they knew something was going
on. The cops on the motorcycles trying
to catch up to him um because probably a
delayed reaction knowing what's going
on. And then here's the depository in
more modern times. Oswald shot from this
corner window on the sixth floor. Um
this is now a museum, so you can walk
around and visit the De Plaza uh on your
own for free. Um, it is a public park.
Um, the book depository building itself
is a museum. It's paid admission, but
it's really worthwhile. It has a lot of
great information, not only on um, the
Kennedy assassination, but also the
legacy of President Kennedy. And then a
block or two away is the Kennedy
Memorial Plaza. It's a memorial to John
F. Kennedy. It's designed by the famous
architect Philip Johnson. It's kind of,
I would say, a little bit controversial
in the sense it's a little bit different
in terms of a memorial, but you have to
remember back in 1963, we didn't really
have a lot of presidential memorials uh
around the country or at least outside
of Washington DC. Um but you know, that
being said, um it is what it is. And
then the I'll check back in with um you
guys, Patty, uh Brad and Joy in just a
moment, but um continuing just for a
second. So the car that Kennedy was shot
and killed in was still used as a
presidential limousine. They convert it
to a hard top though for safety and it
was used for many years after the
assassinations. I mean, how would you
like to be president and driving around
in the car that uh Kennedy was killed
and that's actually what ended up
happening. But if you want to see the
car um it's at the Henry Ford Museum in
Dearborn, Michigan, which oh by the way
also has the Rosa Parks bus among other
things. And here's another view of the
car. Some people are kind of surprised
that it's a hard top, but again, they um
reconfigured it after the shooting and
talk about that other stuff in a minute.
So, Patty, Brad, Joanne, any thoughts on
the latest segment?
>> Yeah, you um I found that remark you
made interesting. You're right. There
were nowhere near as many monuments to
presidents. We we've come to a point in
uh our experience where everything it
seems like is treated as some momentous
occasion. And this event I think really
changed the perspective of a lot of
people on what make what is history
versus what is the stuff that goes along
with history. I'm not sure if I'm making
myself clear, but
>> Oh, yeah. No, I understand. There was a
point when not everything that happened
was considered massive. Um and this
changed I think this began to change it
when I said that the um the uh
conspiracy theories were born with this
event. Yeah. It started a whole
different approach or perspective on
what mattered and and
you know people getting completely
caught up in trivia. Um, and I I think
that is um well, I'm not even going to
use the word again because it does uh
it it does bother me a little bit
because I think it it it's it's it
messes up our perspective on the world
and on life in general.
>> Well, yeah, even in Dallas, I mean, I'm
not a native, so Joan, maybe you can
speak to this, but in Dallas, there was
kind of this uh attempt to kind of
forget about this like um
>> Exactly. Even these historic there, you
can't see it, but there's a historical
marker right here. And then there's
another one further down the road. And
then there's another one over here. Um,
according to locals, those were just
installed a few years ago. For the
longest time, there wasn't really much
here other than that memorial. And then
even this building, um, there was talk
for a long time of tearing it down
because it, you know, uh, the historical
significance of it in a negative way.
Like I I remember seeing an article that
said, um, Tom Landry says book
deposiitories should be torn down. It's
like, well, you know, I appreciate that,
Tom.
>> Did you really say that?
>> Yeah. [laughter] Oh, yeah. You can
Google it like, you know, I appreciate
that, Tom Landry. Great football coach
of the Cowboys, but um yeah, I'd have to
disagree. I think the building should
stay up.
>> Yeah, strongly.
>> But what what about you, Joanne? What do
you What was your kind of thoughts on
Dallas and the response to the um the
assassination?
>> Well, first of all, um anyone who if
you're in Dallas, Dallas area, by all
means, go to the 64 museum. I know a lot
of people who live in Dallas who've
never been there and I say, you know,
you just uh be a tourist in your own
city. You know, just take that Saturday
off and just do it. It's well worth it.
Yeah, there was a lot of controversy
about making a museum out of it. uh
there is this view that you know we
shouldn't remember uh the tragic moments
of our history but you know there's that
cliche that if if we don't remember our
history including the tragic moments we
are destined to repeat it
>> oh yeah no definitely
>> and so yeah I'm I very strongly believe
that uh these moments must be remembered
>> okay well thank you um Patty and Brad
any other thoughts
>> I would agree with that wholeheartedly.
These member these must be remembered
and hopefully
>> yeah the some some perspective on that
nobody's going to deny that the
assassination of of a sitting president
is a historic event. That's not what I
meant by but not every single thing that
happens. And this 24-hour news, I think,
has gotten people hooked on this whole
idea that every moment of every day is a
huge event. And it's not. It's it and it
does screw up the perspective on what is
significantly important and what is
important in passing maybe, but is not
an earthshattering event. That's all I
meant.
>> No, it's okay. Um, let's see. Yeah, if
you get a chance, check out um I think
Clint Hill actually wrote three books.
This was the first one. Um there's a lot
of videos of him um speaking about the
Kennedys. He was really close to Jackie
Kennedy, including after the um
assassination. Got to know her uh really
well and just really interesting
all-around guy. And he actually felt
kind of guilty for he was like, "Oh,
maybe I could have done something."
Which of course is not um true at all.
And and it was interesting. He passed
away a few months ago, and I was really
happy to see the huge outpouring of um
uh condolences and respect for him. Uh
let's see.
I just had one more comment to make
about Dallas, but after the
assassination happened, uh, of course
Dallas got in, you know, the global
news. Um, the city started to really
worry about its reputation,
um, because, you know, there were a lot
of extreme right-wing groups, John
Burchers and, uh, Dallas, they tried to
start making a routinant attempt to show
that yes, we have culture. You know,
Maria Callus had some of her greatest
successes in Dallas.
and um yeah, it's fascinating to see how
the assassination ended up changing
Dallas.
>> Oh, yeah. Um in a big way. And I know
that just from living here a short
period of time and not being um not
being from here. So um all right, let's
continue on. Let's see. Okay, so the I
think these photos, they're um difficult
to look at, but they are interesting. So
this is when the uh Okay, so he was
supposed the motorcade was supposed to
go to the trademark. Um, but then after
he got shot, they didn't go to the
trademark course. They phoned up ahead
to Parkland Hospital and they brought
him in there and Parkland really didn't
have much of warning that he was coming.
Um, that was nicely portrayed, I
thought, in the movie Parkland. Um, but
these are pictures of what's going on
outside and in the hospital. Um,
President Kenny's. So, this is actually
the car. You can see the roses are
strewn all over the back seat. Um, and
you know, Jackie was sitting right here.
President Kennedy was sitting right
here. You can see the shock look on
these people face. They kind of sort of
know what's going on, but uh don't know
all the details. So really, really
interesting um facial expressions in
some of these photos. This is the Secret
Service. Now, again, they don't know
what's going on. Is there like a coup
taking place or is some you know foreign
country trying to attack us or you know
what's happening? So the first uh many
minutes and hours kind of like 911 uh in
certain regards that, you know, people
weren't really sure what was happening.
It took a while to kind of process uh
things. I didn't know it was a lone
individual person.
Um then here's the car
right here. I think they parked it and
then they moved it. They pulled it up a
little bit. So I don't think that was
the original spot. I think
>> um let's see. Here's people kind of
listening in.
>> Oh, what's that?
>> I think you're correct. At first they
just like pulled up and stopped and and
that's what happened. People started
looking into the car and it was pretty
gory. So, somebody had the presence of
mind to move it after a little while.
>> Yeah, it's a black and white photo, but
there would have been blood on the
seats. And so, yeah, they just pulled up
and like, "Oh, hey, wait a minute. It's
not good to leave the car out here.
Let's pull it up closer to the building
and block it off." Um, let's see.
And then, okay, so here's people kind of
listening in on the radio to try and
find out what the heck is going on. Even
though the president's inside, um,
there's not, you know, any news
announcement coming out. Again, this is
before the 24-hour news cycle of like
CNN and social media and all that stuff.
So, news traveled much uh slower back
then. Um, let's see. Some concerned
people was kind of milling about
wondering what's going on.
And
after a while, people started to think
that maybe this wasn't going to work out
because the initial initial thing was,
oh, President Kenny's been shot. Well,
you know, that could mean a lot of
things. It could have mean he just got
grazed in the ear. It could have mean he
got shot in the back, but then okay,
well then he got shot in the head.
That's not going to be a easy thing to
survive.
Uh and then you can see all these
concerned people. So, at this point in
time, it hasn't been announced that uh
President Kenny's been killed. It's just
that he's been shot. Uh maybe some
people know that he's been shot in the
head and he's inside the hospital.
And then the doctors um kind of the
press of course shows up wants to know
what's going on and they're providing a
limited amount of information. They
hadn't really fully publicly announced
um yet all the details of course.
>> Just the way you were saying that
Robert, it reminds me of the actual live
broadcast when the guy realizes what
happened. He says he's been shot.
President Kennedy has been shot. I can I
remember that like clear as day. That's
exactly what what happened as he was
reporting on the motorcade.
>> Yeah. Really really incredible. And we
were talking about this during the
movies like God imagine what would have
been like to you know go through that
experience. This would have been
horrific. Here's doctors kind of um
providing the update. Um and you know of
course the um the situation was not
good. Um, and then so, okay, so this was
a timeline. And again, if you join us a
little bit later, the timeline, I'll
have it extended down to the end of the
page, but later on the program. So, if
you want to, I don't know, take a
screenshot of this or a picture with
your phone, you're more than welcome to
do so, but you probably want to wait
till u we get close to the end. Um, but
anyway, so, okay, so President Kennedy
shot 12:30. Uh, it took only 6 minutes
for the limousine to arrive at the
hospital. Um, and it was only 10 minutes
after he had been shot that Walter
Kankite came on announced that President
Kenny had been shot. We'll actually hear
that clip also a little bit later. And
then, you know, it's pretty incredible
from like a stamina standpoint to think
that President Kenny was shot in the
head and he lived for 30 minutes. That's
pretty unbelievable. Um, those shots are
usually immediately fatal. Um, so that's
pretty incredible. Now, of course,
eventually the news comes out that um
the president has died. And so, these
are pictures of people um that have
heard the news of what's happened and of
course much more um emotion. So, the
pictures before were kind of more like
concern um and now the grief and the
shock and the anger um and all that
stuff is setting. And there's actually a
ton of photos from this part of the
event. I could probably show you a
hundred. I kind of had to kind of narrow
it down to the um say more interesting
um or noteworthy ones. But
>> Dan Paulson mentioned something that
really is a historical detail just
because I bet you there are people
watching this that don't even know what
a phone booth is. But [laughter]
yes, that the reporters that were on
scene were like rushing to the any phone
booth that was available and then
wouldn't leave because there wasn't
another phone anywhere and nobody had a
cell phone at the moment. So,
>> yeah.
>> Yeah. Really limited uh phone capability
back then.
>> Yep.
>> How are you going to get a hold of
somebody?
>> Yes. It's so hard to believe there was a
time when people didn't have cell
phones. [laughter]
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah.
I remember my dad used to travel for
work and, you know, he would as soon as
the plane would land, he'd have to go to
the pay phone and call us and we'd be
sitting by the phone waiting. And of
course, there was no internet so we
couldn't tell if the plane was delayed
or not. just all the Superman trying to
change into a suit in a cell phone.
>> Yeah, exactly. Um, this is a really
touching photo. There's a lot of really
fascinating photos related to the
Kennedy assassin. This one is an
interesting one. So, this is Robert
Kennedy. He was back in um he he lived
outside of Washington DC in the Northern
Virginia sub, but he's at home and he's
just gotten the news that President his
brother, the president's been shot. Now,
at this point in time, um it hadn't been
announced that he was killed. um and he
just so happened to be with his children
at this point in time. So you can see
he's um comforting his kids, probably
just trying to process what's going on.
But this is when uh moments after he got
the news that his brother had been shot,
but at this point in time um the further
details that he had been killed had not
come out yet, but a touching photo
nonetheless. And of course, Robert
Kennedy himself would be assassinated
five years later. Um and then this is
Johnson. So initially Johnson's holed up
inside the hospital. Um, and once
President Kennedy was um, pronounced
dead, okay, now he's the president and
again, people don't know what the heck
is going on. Is this some kind of coup
or um is this foreign government trying
to take over or something? Uh, and so
they decide, well, you know, you got to
get Johnson out of here um and get him
on a plane and get the heck out of here
because this is too hot, so to speak, of
a um situation. And then kron kite comes
on and announces that uh Kennedy first
he announced that Kennedy had been shot.
Uh and then a little bit later he
announced that Kennedy had been killed.
We'll actually show a clip of that in a
little bit later as well. Um all right,
let's pause for the recording so we can
check out these.
So a really incredible paradox is kind
of the happiness and the joy of uh
Jaclyn Kennedy and President John F.
Kennedy um disembarking Air Force One.
Um and then a short time later uh after
President Kennedy died, you know, they
had to get a casket and put him inside.
And so this is the Secret Service and
they're actually carrying the casket
that has President Kennedy in it um back
into Air Force One. Um and you know,
this was not long after um they had
disembarked the plane. And you can
actually see Jackie over here on the
right
watch. That's her husband. You know, he
just got murdered alongside of her. Um
and then I always thought this is a
really incredibly sad photo. is Jackie
um climbing up into Air Force One all by
herself, you know, and the the paradox
between this photo where she's coming
down the stairs. She's with her husband.
It's this great day. She's really happy.
And then, you know, you fast forward uh
less than an hour and a half later and
she's climbing up the stairs by herself
with her husband in a casket. He'd been
killed. Um so just an unbelievable turn
of events um in such a short period of
time. Can't think of anything in
American history with the exception of
maybe like I don't know 911 or Pearl
Harbor or something where something so
monumental.
>> Wait a rider.
>> What's that?
>> Oh, sorry. I didn't know I had my mic
on.
>> Oh, it's okay. No problem. But yeah,
just really incredible um turn events,
but yeah, really sad photo uh to see
Jackie walking up the stairs um of Air
Force One all by herself after um you
know, coming down it. Um let's see. So
then remember uh Jackie just 15 weeks
earlier had lost her son Patrick and so
now she's dealing with this death of her
husband. So the fact that she was able
to kind of maintain her composure as
well as she did um after the death of
her husband is incredible. But you
combine that with the fact that she had
also lost her son uh gosh what a tough
15-week stretch for her.
And someone made a great comment that
this was the end of Camelot.
And you know, I think it's so poignant
because it just shows the fra how the
fragility of life.
>> Oh yeah. Can end at any time. And sorry,
I misspoke earlier. I said an hour and a
half. It was actually um 2 hours and 36
minutes. So they got off the plane at
11:44 and he was shot and then died and
then they left the hospital and they
reboarded the plane uh 2 hours and 36
minutes later. So wow.
Um and then okay, so this is the
timeline if you want to take a picture
of this or a screenshot of this. So
again they land at Love Field 11:38. 14
minutes later, 11:52, the presidential
motorcade leaves Lovefield. Um 12:30,
the president shot. Uh six minutes
later, the limousine arrives at
Parkland. Kron kite remember initially
he came on. They didn't have the vid the
camera set up, so he just had to talk um
that uh President Kennedy had been shot.
Uh 100 p.m. 30 minutes later after the
shooting, it was announced that uh
President or the hospital determined
President Kennedy died. Um Johnson got
the heck out of there because they were
worried for his safety. Um Oswald was
captured relatively quickly. We'll talk
about that um a little bit later. And
then 208, President Kennedy's body and
Mrs. Kenny depart Parkland Hospital. Uh
Lyndon Johnson sworn in as president at
238.
So an hour and 38 minutes after
President Kenny was pronounced dead. Um,
the Air Force One left Love Field at
2:47 and it arrived back in Washington
DC at Andrews Air Force Base at 558.
Now, these times here are all Texas time
or Central time and this particular one
is Eastern time. That would have been
>> 458. What's that?
I um that wasn't me, but I just wanted
to make one point regarding Camelot
wasn't born until that William
Manchester interview um sometime after
the burial had already happened,
>> but that's too
>> confused, you know. [laughter]
>> Yeah, we'll talk we'll talk about that
in just a minute as well. Um let's see
because yeah, I have some more
information about half that. So, this is
um inside Air Force One. The plane's not
departed yet. Uh they wanted Johnson to
take the oath before he actually um
before the plane took off just for like
I don't know safety, security purpose,
whatever. You can see Jackie uh in her
bloodstained pink Chanel suit standing
right next to him. Uh here's Lady. I
mean imagine I I feel like the term
surreal is overused, but god what a
surreal moment this must have been for
her. She's standing next to uh Johnson
taking the oath for office to replace
her president who' just been murdered um
alongside of her in the motorcade.
>> And compare that look of shock to the to
the beautiful smiles she had had just an
hour or two earlier.
>> Well, and Judge Sarah Hughes is
administering the oath. And um you know
Texas nowadays it gets on worst uh worst
states for women list but at one time
people were saying what do they put in
the water because the state had so many
powerful pioneering women.
>> Yes is one of them.
>> Yeah that's a great point.
>> Molly Ians. Yeah.
>> Yes. Molly [laughter]
and Armstrong. Janice Joplain. Uh Sarah
W. Richard long. Yeah. Anne Richards.
Lady Bird Johnson.
Yeah.
>> Oh yeah. Lady Bird Johnson. She was a
multi-millionaire businesswoman um
before she became first lady. Um and
then you know so the that was kind of
one another disappointment in the Jackie
film. They kind of really showed her all
alone after the swearing in. And you
know maybe she felt that way emotionally
but um the photos are very different
than the way it was. And you can see the
people, you know, standing around
comforting her. Um, and you know, just a
state of shock of, you know, what's
transpired and what's taking place. So
then after the oath of office, um, they
end up departing for Washington DC.
Again, not sure what the heck is going
on. They want to get Johnson airborne,
thinking maybe he's probably a little
bit safer there. And, uh, of course, the
safest place, um, they're thinking is
back in Washington DC. Similar thing to
President Bush in 9/11. They wanted to
get him the heck out of the school where
he was at and get him airborne. um just
because they're not sure what's going
on. Um but you know, there's still a
country to run and so who knows, maybe
this might be some kind of uh foreign
power trying to take over the United
States by toppling the uh government
hierarchy. So they're kind of briefing
him on what's going on. And of course,
they also want to know what about the
shooter and you know what's the
situation with that
>> and most of the people that were
responsible for keeping the country
going were not able to talk to each
other as all this was happening. So
>> yeah,
>> very confusing for people who were
trying to make decisions at the time or
very stressful, shall we say.
>> Yeah, thanks for mentioning that Patty.
Um I appreciate that. Um so okay, Air
Force One takes off heading back to
Washington DC although with a new
president. Um President Kennedy's body
is in a coffin um inside the airplane.
If you actually want to see this Air
Force One that was used, it's on
display. It's at the really an excellent
museum, the National Museum of the
United States Air Force, which is in
Dayton, Ohio, which is north of
Cincinnati. It's really a great museum
to visit, not just because of this
plane, but the whole um Air Force
history. And oh, was someone going to
say something? No, I was just going to
say that was one of the reasons they
wanted to get back to the plane because
that was the only place that they had a
more complex communication system so
they could actually communicate with
Washington.
>> Yeah, a lot easier to Great point,
Patty. A lot easier to communicate from
here than like say some back room at
Parkland Hospital. They got more of the,
you know, people and infrastructure all
in one place. Yeah. Problem with with uh
President Bush on 911 on Air Force One.
>> Apparently, he found the communications
they couldn't do any video or anything.
>> Yeah. So, they've redone that.
>> Yeah, that's a great point. I mean, even
back then, um which was not that long
ago, he ran into a lot of technical
problems trying to communicate with
during all that. Um
>> yeah, even telephone infrastructure gets
overwhelmed, especially back 60 some odd
years ago. So, Mhm. Um, let's see. So,
eventually the plane arrives back in
Washington DC. This is the casket of
President Kennedy being uh taken off Air
Force One.
And then here's Jackie. So, when the
plane landed, Robert Kennedy uh rushed
on board to greet Jackie. Uh I really I
thought this was very chivalous of him.
Um a little bit different than the way
he was depicted in the Jackie film. Uh
rushes on board the plane. He didn't
want Jackie coming off the plane. you
know, all by herself. Um, so you can see
there he's holding her hand. Um, and
he's with her by her side. Um, President
Kennedy's body has been put inside this
hear.
And then here she is. You can still see
the blood on her suit
and just, you know, the state of shock
that must have been. I I wasn't alive
during the President Kennedy
assassination and it wasn't the same
exact event, but I remember 9/11 and
just for how many hours I was shocked of
what had happened. I didn't even have
any personal connections to 911 just the
and you can imagine these people at this
point in time that you know were
experiencing this live and in person how
um difficult that must have been. And
this top story in the news um was
someone going to say something? It
wasn't until this moment, which was
quite a few hours later, that Johnson
was even able to speak to the American
people. And that was a huge moment, too.
>> Mhm.
>> Because we were all cut off. We didn't
know what was happening. It was all
happening after all that kind of live
television that nobody really knew
anything cuz everything was happening on
board Air Force One and between Air
Force One and Washington. So, it was
like this long period where it's like,
"So, now what?"
>> Yeah. And why did this happen and who
did it and all that kind of stuff. Took
a while for that to get out. Thanks,
Patty. Appreciate you mentioning that.
>> Um, of course, this was top story in the
news. It It's really uh I always find it
maybe because I like media and I like
history. It's always fascinating uh to
go back and read like historical
accounts of some um important event
that's taken place whether it was the
Kennedy assassination or the Civil War
or World War II or Vietnam or whatever.
So um just interesting going through
these different um media coverages of
the event that took place. Here's an
interesting photo. Of course, this was
top news for an extended period of time.
Um let's see. So, this is a famous
Saturday Evening Post cover by Norman
Rockwell. Um, and then they reused the
portrait for the memorial issue to
President Kennedy. And when I lived in
Washington DC, I knew this guy that
actually worked at the White House. He
wasn't like uh officially working for
President Kennedy, but I did see him on
a regular basis. And he told me that
this portrait he thought was the most
realistic, lifelike uh depiction of
President Kennedy that he had seen. So
I'm like, "Oh, that's good enough for
me." Um, so the gentleman really liked
that particular portrait. Um, and then
let's talk about the aftermath. So
Oswald was only 24 years old when he
shot and killed Kennedy. I really didn't
want to spend a ton of time um, talking
about him, just, you know, I don't want
to glamorize his uh, life or what he
did, but talk about him a little bit
briefly. He was 24 years old when he got
killed. Um, one of the sad aspects of
the story, in addition to President
Kennedy being killed, this gentleman was
also killed. This is Dallas police
officer JD Tippet, he was 39 years old,
a family man. Um, he encountered Oswald
on a street. How they caught Oswald was
they knew he worked in the book
depository and after they realized the
shots came from the book depository.
They sealed it off and they did a roll
call of all the employees and they
discovered that one employee was missing
and it was Oswald and he had only worked
there a short period of time. I don't
remember how long exactly he'd been
there but he was kind of an eccentric to
begin with and so we're like you know
what everyone's here except for him. uh
the shooting took place in this
building, so maybe it's him. So then the
people that were working with him
described what he was wearing. They put
out All Points Bulletin. Uh Tippet is
out on patrol in area of Dallas known as
Oak Cliff, which is a um short distance
from downtown. And he sees a guy that
fits the description of Oswald. And so
he pulls his car up alongside of him.
Now, we don't know the exact exchange
that took place because both of these
people ended up getting killed, but
supposedly Tippet pulled up his car
alongside Oswald. He rolled down the
passenger window and started talking to
Oswald. And then uh Tippet parked his
car and got out of the driver's side,
proceeded around the front of the car.
Oswald pulled out a gun and shot and
killed him and then took off running.
Now, fortunately, two people saw Tippet
get shot and they immediately ran inside
their homes and called police and were
able to scribe Oswald. And so, that
creates a euphoria of police looking for
him further. Um, this is actually
Tippet's car. So, you picture him again.
He gets a bulletin to be on the lookout
for this guy with a description of
Oswald. They don't know that he shot the
president, but he's a suspect. Um, Oz or
Tippet pulls his car down the street. Um
he rolls down the passenger window,
speaks to Oswald. Again, not sure what
he said because um Tippet was killed and
Oswald was killed shortly thereafter.
Then he steps out of his car and walks
around the front and when he does um
Oswald pulls a gun out of his jacket and
shoots and kills him. And this there's a
historical marker to uh JD Tippet at
this spot. If you're in Dallas, it's in
the Oakliff section of the city. Um here
is Tippet's wife and his three children.
And of course they were left fatherless.
And so it's sad. He's he's kind of like
the forgotten man um of the Kennedy
assassin, but he was killed too. He lost
his life and uh you know he's a family
man. Um so really sad story. He was only
39 years old.
And then um the all points bulletin goes
out for this guy who shot the cop. And
how Oswald got finally caught is he
ducked into a shoe store uh not far from
where he shot Tippet. And there was all
these police sirens that were heading
towards where the officer was shot. And
everybody was going out on the street to
see what was going on. There's all these
sirens wailing and cop cars whizzing by
and everybody was looking to see what
the heck was going on except for this
one guy who was like ducked in the shoe
store and was kind of like looking out
the window kind of suspiciously to see
what's going on. Then he left the store,
but his suspicious behavior caught the
attention of one of the employees. The
employee followed him down the street a
few doors and a woman that was working
the ticket counter at the Texas theater
went out in the street to see what was
going on with all the sirens. Oswald
snuck in behind her so he didn't have to
buy a ticket and into the movie theater.
And then the gentleman who had the
wherewithal to follow him from the shoe
store. Uh told the woman to call the
police because she thought his behavior
was suspicious. The cops show up. They
tell him what happens. They go inside
and confront Oswald. Um he puts up a
tussle. Um but they eventually subdue
him and they take him into custody. And
this is actually Oswald um being
escorted out of the theater. Um, so it's
actually pretty incredible police work
and also work by just regular everyday
citizens helping the police that Oswald
was able to be captured um so quickly.
He was uh apprehended an hour and 20
minutes after he shot John F. Kenny.
That's really incredible. Um so good
that they got him. Uh and then of course
he's arrested and taken to the police
station and there's kind of a bunch of
crazy stuff goes on with him. But um lo
and behold uh Jack Ruby, he shows up on
the scene. another interesting character
in the story. Um, and he was not happy
about uh Oswald and there's a big whole
debate on what his motivations were, but
he ends up uh learning that Oswald's
going to be transported from one police
facility to another. He shows up there
and with a gun shoots Oswald and kills
him, which adds a whole another uh crazy
dimension to this story. This is a
famous photo of Ruby shooting Oswald.
And then here's the same uh event from
another angle. This gentleman's actually
a Texas uh Ranger police officer.
And Oswald did not make it. He survived
for a little while, but then eventually
he um passed away. So no trial uh for
him. He was shot and killed. And then of
course that's big news as well. Uh
assassin Oswald slain in Dallas.
And then the Kennedy funeral takes
place. We'll talk about in a minute. Um
Brad, Joy, Patty, any thoughts on this
segment?
>> This was the what was filling up the
dead space in between when we learned um
that he'd been killed, that Kennedy had
been killed and the plane landing in DC.
Most of it was about these odds and
ends. I mean, these thing these things
were filtering through because now by
now all the TV stations were on full
fullbore uh news. So all these little
tidbits were um
you know were getting uh filtered out
and it was getting like you're saying
more bizarre by the moment and that
following Sunday when when uh Oswald was
killed right there in the police
station. It was sort of like you know
nothing else more bizarre can happen
except by now you're prepared for
anything bizarre to happen at any
moment. It was just such a weird
sensation. all this crazy stuff
happening.
>> Oh yeah. I asked my um mom about it and
that was like her main memory just how
this dominated the media coverage, you
know, television, newspaper, just even
talking with neighbors and friends. I
mean, this was the the only thing people
were talking about for days on end.
until Saturday
>> that that afternoon, that Friday, these
bits and these bizarre bits and pieces,
you know, coming across, but they were
just little sentences because nobody
really did know what was happening
because people on the street were trying
to fill in, you know, the police who
were showing up here and there, but none
of this was, you know, being really
communicated thoroughly to the nation.
So, it was just it it's hard to explain
how
just shocking everything was because you
couldn't predict anything anymore.
Nothing was predictable at this point.
>> Yeah, businesses closed. Um, yeah, Brad
and Joan, any other thoughts on this
segment?
I agree with the chaos that was going on
nationwide. And for once, all four or
all three networks were on news 24 hours
[clears throat] several days.
>> I think it's interesting seeing the
Texas police officers with their cowboy
hats on.
>> Yeah, the Texas Rangers.
I I thought that the scenes uh in the
Parkland movie with the Oswell family
were were well done and they they did
seem true to what was was coming out,
you know, for the several weeks after
the uh assassination. It it was very
true and again I think he they made that
point um about what he had done to his
whole family as well. I mean not just
the country but he had really destroyed
so many lives.
>> Yeah. His mother was completely nuts at
the end there.
>> Yeah, exactly. Um Patty, thanks for
reminding me. But okay. Yeah, so the
Kennedy um shooting took place Friday,
November 22nd. This is when Ruby, this
is his mug shot. So yeah, uh Oswald got
killed on Sunday. So he wasn't around
long. It didn't really have much to say
u before he exited the stage door, left,
so to speak. Um,
>> and at the same time, Jin Washington, as
this is happening, they're preparing to
move the body to the Capitol Ratunda.
>> It just was, it's so hard to explain
>> how crazy this three three days and
several weeks thereafter. I mean,
Thanksgiving was the next week
>> and can't even imagine what Thanksgiving
was like right after this. It was just
>> bizarre.
Oh yeah.
>> Yeah. And this had such a it had a
tremendous ripple effect. It completely
changed Marina Oswald's life. I mean I
have to admit I feel sorry for her.
>> Yes.
>> And um
also it reminds me of you know in Madmen
they did a sess they did an episode on
the assassination and how people were
reacting.
>> Oh yeah that was a great episode.
>> Just glued to the TV screens. And
remember one fella says who's not paying
that much attention to it said he said
I'm not in love with this tragedy.
>> Yeah, that was a really incredible um
episode as well. Uh I forgot to mention
you can see the uh the guy here. He's
actually got Oswald handcuffed. Um so
and then of course the shot was fatal.
So interesting. And they actually took
him to Parkland Hospital which they
showed in the um Parkland movie. That
was kind of uh bizarre. But yeah, you
can actually the house that Oswald um
him and his wife split up and she was
staying with a friend. You can actually
go visit that house. It's in Irving,
Texas. If you're familiar with Dallas,
[laughter] we had a organized a tour of
it um last year. It was really
fascinating to go um see that. And then
kind of fast forward to the funeral. So
here's President Kennedy lying and stay
at the capital which they end up doing
for um
>> so this is transfer happened shortly a
within hours after Oswald was shot and
>> yeah the story is still you know
developing and they don't know all the
details like we do now um people still
processing and the shock of that um
let's see so yeah this is the capital
rotunda
>> people were actually in church here in
New England when when Oswald was shot.
That's where I was.
>> Oh, yeah. Wow.
>> I learned when I came out of church.
Yes.
>> Really? That's interesting.
>> Um, let's see. Here is Jackie at the
coffin of her husband. Now, imagine how
difficult this would be. Imagine your
significant other passes away and you go
to their funeral. Imagine doing it in
front of, you know, hundreds and
thousands of people and it's being
photographed and broadcast on
television. I mean, you can't even uh
mourn in private, at least not at this
particular aspect. So, how incredibly
difficult that must have been. Um,
>> and imagine trying to deal with the
father of your young children and your
husband and you're also the
responsibility of this nation in total
shock.
>> Oh, yeah. Mhm. Um, matching photo of
them leaving the capital.
Then here's the hearse with the casket
and going through the streets of
Washington.
And then this is the casket departing
the White House for
>> although they're going to make a stop at
the church first.
>> The walk was was from the White House to
the church. Yes.
>> Yeah. Several block I think eight blocks
I thought they said in the film. Um, and
there's I've seen not this particular
photo, but um photos of this particular
event, the more famous one is in just a
moment. There is Jackie. She's walking
with Bobby Kennedy and Ted Kennedy.
And I assume the reason they had in her
dialogue with Jack Valente, the reason
they had that remark about De Gal was
because
for the people watching this, that was a
big shock to see a figure like De Gal or
the figure who was de Gaul um actually
walking in this procession because
apparently nobody thought he would stoop
to that level. But apparently it was his
uh admiration for Jacqueline Kennedy
that he agreed to do that. So I I don't
think that exchange actually probably
happened, but that was why it was put in
there because that was such a shock to
see Deal walking in session.
>> Yeah. De Gaul said that Jackie taught
the world how to behave.
>> Yes.
>> This is um one of the more famous photos
of the aftermath. Jackie walking with
Bobby and Ted.
Look at Teddy. He looks like a baby boy
in that picture.
>> Oh, yeah. Very young. Um, and then this
is a famous sequence of events. So, this
is outside the church.
And again, there's Ted and Bobby with
Jackie with her two kids. And then
here's the famous salute John Junior
gave.
And wow, imagine how things changed in
just uh from Friday to Monday.
And President Kennedy is buried at
Arlington National Cemetery, which I
recommend visiting if you get a chance.
>> I believe Rose Kennedy was in that shot,
but I I it went by too fast for me to
see if if I could see her. No, I guess
she's like sliding off to the right
there.
>> But that's those are the sisters. His uh
two two of his sisters and
>> I'm not sure if that's Pat or not.
>> Um let's see. So one reason why
President Kennedy was buried in
Arlington Cemetery. Well, this is a
whole interesting story as well. Um his
family wanted him buried in
Massachusetts. They actually talked
about that briefly in the um Jackie
film. Uh she was really adamant though
that he should be buried at Arlington
National Cemetery which as a person who
lived in Washington DC I can really
respect her um decision to override his
family and that must have been somewhat
courageous on her part. Um, Jackie
Kennedy uh had to do a talk on her again
because she really accomplished a lot as
first lady and in learning about the
history of Arlington Cemetery. It's
always been an important place, but when
President Kennedy was buried there,
which was her decision, it really took
the popularity of it to a whole another
level and really kind of helped made it
um the place that it stayed. Jackie made
that call and against the wishes of his
family, they were putting a lot of
pressure on her uh to have him buried in
Massachusetts, but she decided not to.
Interestingly enough, uh just 11 days
before the assassination, the Kennedes
visited Arlington National Cemetery, and
it has, if you've never been there
before, it has this great panoramic view
of the city. It's on a hill in
Arlington, Virginia. Uh and then across
the Ptoac River is uh Washington DC.
It's one of the best views that you're
going to get of Washington DC is from
Arlington Cemetery. And so, uh, John F.
Kennedy and Jaclyn Kennedy were there
and legend has it that he said to her,
uh, looking out over the across the
PTOIC to Washington DC, "This place is
so beautiful. I could stay here forever
and then end up doing just that."
And this is the view from the Kennedy
Grave site. And this particular photo is
not the best. It's the best one in the
public. domain I could find. But again,
this is Washington DC off here in the
distance. This is the Washington
Monument. Uh this is the Capitol over
here. This is the Battoomeac River. Um
so really incredible view. And then of
course this is the grave site with uh
President Kennedy and the eternal flame.
Uh here's some pictures from the
funeral. That's
>> Here's his mother right there. Yeah.
>> And again, still a very griefstricken
nation.
And
>> Jackie was very afraid that she that uh
the same thing that happened to Mary
Todd Lincoln would happen to her.
>> Oh yeah. She Mary Todd Lincoln really uh
a lot of financial problems after she
left. They didn't have the
infrastructure in place to support um
widows even of presidents.
Um let's see. And then the funeral
taking place at Arlington burial.
Here's Jackie. And here's Bobby.
>> And this this went on for so long. Of
course, like so many things, it took a
lot everything took a lot longer than
was anticipated. It was actually getting
dark before uh by the time she was
lighting the flame, it was actually
getting dark.
>> Yeah, you can see the sun. Uh that's
excellent point, Patty. You can see the
sun here is starting to set.
And then this is after he was buried. So
initially um they didn't do the
elaborate grave site because this was so
kind of impromptu. Um but again I don't
want to make it sound like Arlington
Cemetery was a place that nobody visited
and then President Kennedy was buried
there and it became a major tourist. But
my point is it really went to like a
whole another level um after he was
buried there and that was really
Jackie's um decision. So kudos to her.
Um, if you go visit President Kennedy's
grave site, there's really three kind of
main uh tourist attractions in
Arlington. One is the Kennedy grave
site, the other is the Tomb of the
Unknown Soldier, and the third being the
Lee Custous House, which formerly was uh
inhabited by Robert E. Lee. That's a
whole another story for another day.
We'll let Harry uh dive into that.
Here's the Kennedy grave site. And this
is John F. Kennedy and Jacqueline's
grave. She was later buried there after
she passed away. And then the two on the
side, it's not John Jr., he was buried
at sea. It's their daughter, Arabella.
She was actually still born before um
they
>> before he was elected.
>> And then their son, Patrick, who I said
died shortly before um President Kenny
passed away. This is the Lee Custous
House in the background.
>> And Robert, is Robert Kennedy? Where is
Robert Kennedy buried?
>> He's buried there, too, but he's off to
the side. Um,
>> Eddie.
>> Yes. Um, so yeah, you can see John F.
Kennedy born 1917. He died in 1963.
There's the eternal flame.
Um, let's see, there's the grave site.
And then we were talking about this
before. So, uh, Jacqueline Kennedy is
the one who actually coined the term
Camelot. She gave an interview um,
shortly after President Kennedy passed
away to a family friend. Um and this is
a quote that she said now this is kind
of a um summation of different things
that transpire. She said in this
interview, "President Kennedy was
strongly attracted to Camelot because he
was an idealist who saw history as
something made by heroes like King
Arthur at night before we'd go to sleep.
Jack liked to play some records." And
the song he loved the most came at the
very end of this record, the last sight
of Camelot, which goes, "Don't let it be
forgot that once there was a spot for
one brief shining moment that was known
as Camelot." And then she goes on to
say, "There will be great presidents
again, but there will never be another
Camelot." And so Jaclyn Kennedy actually
is the one who coined the term Camelot
to describe the Kennedy administration.
So interesting tidbit for you there.
Camelot was a popular musical of the
era. And then another thing that um
Kennedy impact on Washington DC and the
nation as a whole is the Kennedy Center.
Um the John F. Kennedy and Jaclyn
Kennedy were really a driving force
behind this being established. Um there
had been long talk of needing a
performing arts center in Washington DC.
It had been stuck in the mud, so to
speak, for years, literally and
figuratively speaking. uh the Kennedys
come into the White House. They kind of
threw their um influence and powers of
persuasion behind it, got the um
building going, so to speak, and then
when he died, it was um decided that
this would be um named after President
Kennedy, be his living memorial. So,
they don't in Washington DC, you know,
there's the Washington Monument and the
Lincoln Memorial and all that kind of
stuff. This is the memorial for
President Kennedy. Sometimes people are
on the mall and they're like, "Hey,
where's how come there's no memorial
here for Kennedy like there is for
Washington and Lincoln and Roosevelt and
all that stuff?" Well, this is the
memorial to President Kennedy. It's a
living memorial. Um, and really
beautiful structure. If you ever get a
chance, you're living in Washington DC,
if you haven't been to the Kennedy
Center, make sure you check it out. Or
if you're visiting from out of town, uh,
just an incredible number of great
performing arts um, things take place
there. Uh they have this famous statue
of President Kennedy on the inside. Go
check that out. And lit up at night
which is really beautiful. It's right
along the Ptoic River. And oh, when I
look at these pictures of the Arlington
Cemetery and um the Kennedy Center, it
just brings back so many fond memories
of the years that I lived in Washington
DC. I lived in Washington DC uh eight
years the first time uh and five years
the second time. So 13 years altogether
and just uh nothing but fond memories of
my time there. Um we were talking about
the President Kennedy
rating by the C-SPAN presidential
historian survey. He was voted eighth
most or eighth best president in
history. Um so that's kind of one of his
lasting impacts so to speak on our
nation and the world. And then this was
the speech that Kennedy, this is an
excerpt of the speech that Kennedy was
supposed to deliver at the trademark.
Um, but of course he was shot and killed
and wasn't able to deliver this. We in
this country, in this generation, are by
destiny rather than choice the watchmen
of the walls of world freedom. We ask,
therefore, that we may be worthy of our
power and responsibility, that we may
exercise our strength with wisdom and
restraint, and that we may achieve in
our time and for all time the ancient
vision of peace on earth, goodwill
toward men. That must always be our
goal, and the righteousness of our cause
must always underly our strength. For as
we as was written long ago, except the
Lord keep the city, the watchman waketh,
but in vain. Um part of his his
attraction was his talent for um
>> words,
>> creating inspiration through aspiration.
>> Yes, I would agree with that, Patty. Um
let's see. So, a few more things to go
and then we'll wrap it up. Um I actually
have some more videos if you're
interested, but I'll play those at the
very end. John F. Kennedy, born May
29th, 1917. He was killed on November
22nd, 1963.
His wife Jackie passed away in 1994. She
eventually left Washington DC, moved to
New York City, and lived the rest of her
life based out of there. And
>> she Greece,
>> what's that?
>> Until she went to Greece.
>> Well, yes. Yeah, she did have [laughter]
briefs in uh Greece. If, as I mentioned
earlier, if you want to learn about the
Kennedy wedding, um, I recorded on our
YouTube channel, took place in 1953. Um,
let's see. Upcoming programs we have
related to history. Wednesday, we're
doing the Pilgrims American Experience
documentary or docu, I guess you could
say. Uh, we're repeating the Rosa Parks
film on Monday, December 1st. And on the
19th, we're doing our Elellanar
Roosevelt documentary that we had to
postpone from a few weeks ago. And we've
been recording this program. We'll post
on our YouTube channel. I'll send out
the link as soon as it's available, but
keep in mind it's probably going to take
a few days for me to do that. Um, let's
see. Let's circle back with our
distinguished panel of experts, Patty,
[laughter] Brad, and Joanne. Any
thoughts on the Kennedy before So, we're
not done. We still have a couple more
videos I'll play. Um, but any final
thoughts before we queue up the last
videos and call it a night. So on that
Monday, so that whole day right into
evening um was taken up with this whole
final goodbye and I don't think there
was a dry eye anywhere. And that's
Monday and two day three days later
we're trying to have some kind of
Thanksgiving and everybody was still
kind of walking around like zombies
trying to understand what you know how
to process all this. It it was a very
very very sad and bizarre time.
Yeah, I can imagine that
>> relatives seeing each other that you
know you see each other at holidays but
nobody knows really what to say to each
other because it's all been said and
it's none of it's been said. It's like
there's more tears and but it's not a
time for tears and it's it was just you
know I was young enough that I had never
really lived through anything that that
extraordinary before and it it just was
so bizarre for so long. Even Christmas I
think was still very because you
normally have the tree lighting ceremony
and I think they if I'm not if I'm not
mistaken they skipped that or at least
didn't do it until much later. Mhm.
>> Okay. Brad and Joanne, what about you?
Any final thoughts before we queue up
the final videos and call it a night?
>> It normally when a president dies, they
they keep the flag in morning for 30
days. So, I think Patty was right. I
think the uh it would have been till
December 22nd.
So, if they were going to have a public
celebration of Christmas, it wouldn't
have been until the morning period was
over.
>> I think I think you're right. That's
exactly what happened. It was It was
after the 30 days. It was just before
Christmas that they did that. Yeah. And
it was still very subdued.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Joanne, what about you? Any final
thoughts before we queue up the last
videos and call it a night?
>> Well, yes. I think it's interesting to
see what um you know, millennials and
Zoomers their their whole approach to um
you know, this history. Um because you
know Jack um Jackie said well Jack's
view of history was like as a hero
heroic pursuit. [snorts] We are growing
up in an era and I think it's quite
healthy where we realize that history is
complicated
and we have to parse out how should I
say the
the uh complexities and you know the
mistakes the great leaders did but also
respect the truly extraordinary things
they did in this country.
Oh, yeah. Great point.
>> Yeah. One thing I
>> Yeah. One thing I'm absolutely sure of
is those pictures, the photos were just
so beautiful, so charismatic that
they're never ever going to be
forgotten. You know, every generation
that comes after us is going to remember
them. And they're, you know, we're going
to get more and more books about the
Kennedy family. That's all there is to
it.
>> It's more movies and mineries and all
that stuff. more from Robert and you
know that kind of stuff. [laughter]
>> Yeah, your comments Joanne too that
that's why cynicism bothers me because
you tend to lose the threads and and so
you you get stuck on a on a negative
path. Um and you it's harder to pick out
what the heroic things are and what the
complicating things are. it because you
start following a rabbit hole kind of
thing and yeah, cynicism just it never
goes anywhere. It other than it takes
you off the rails basically.
>> Well, in my research, in my travels, I
think there are four approaches people
take to historic figures. They either
idolize them, they honor them, they just
acknowledge them, or they trash them.
And I think the idea is to stay in that
honor zone. stay out of the idolatry
zone. Um, stay out of the well, they did
great work. However, they did this and
this and that that. Yeah, that's
acknowledgement is probably cynicism.
And uh, you know, definitely the the
family had its problems, but they don't
deserve to be trashed.
>> Okay, [clears throat] that's a good
point.
>> It's sort of like the idea when when
people get into arguments over like
whether somebody was a saint or not. And
I like to point out to people that
having lived in a tradition that does
recognize saints, saints are usually
people known for their journey from
clayfooted human beinghood into greater
insights. Okay? So you can't really
become a saint if you haven't had feet
of clay.
>> And that's exactly one reason why Alice
Paul was one of my favorite historic
figures. I had that same type of
background, Patty. And I remember when
Martin Luther King was assassinated, you
know, sis sister said, uh, we had to
stand in silence in honor of his
martyrdom. And I was very much raised
with that. [laughter]
And so, yes, so that's exactly why I
have such a deep respect for the heroism
and the brilliance of Alice Paul. Well,
you know, Joanne, it's interesting that
you mentioned that because when you
first came in with that remark before
Robert had introduced you, I saw the
Alice Paul comment and I immediately
went to look for what the content had
said because she's one of my heroes as
well.
>> Okay. Well, that's excellent. Um, let's
see. So, let's call it a night because
we've been going on for quite a
[clears throat] while. Um, so I do have
three short videos to play. They're all
very short. Um, let me stop the
recording so we can cue that up. And
thanks for joining us. Especially thanks
to our distinguished panel.